(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-04T23:30:25.928069",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
のじゃーーー！
Nojaaa!
あらあら メラメラ あちち メラ！
My, my! Flare, flare! So hot, flare!
アソビ部あまり第一、火消しサラマンダーのあちちメラなのじゃ！
I'm Achichi Mera, the firefighter salamander, the first member of the leftover Play Club!
のじゃ～
Noja~
こんばんは。のじゃばんは。
Good evening. Good evening-noja.
のじゃばんは。
Good evening-noja.
おぬしのじゃばんは。
Good evening-noja to you.
あ、アンケートで高評価をお願いするの忘れてたのじゃ、今入れるのじゃ。
Ah, I forgot to ask for likes in the poll-noja. I'll add it now-noja.
高評価押してほしいのじゃ。よいしょ。
I want you to press the like button-noja. Heave-ho.
したのじゃ。
There we go.
こ、いいのじゃ。
Y- Yes, this is good.
よいしょ。よいしょ。
Heave-ho. Heave-ho.
遅れた？
Am I late?
遅れたのじゃ。
I was late-noja.
よし！
Alright!
こんばんはなのじゃ～、のじゃばんは～
Good evening-noja~ Good evening-noja~
今日は、今日は元々、
Today, today, originally...
元々の予定じゃと、元々の予定じゃと
according to the original plan, according to the original plan...
リズム天国で遊ばせていただく予定だったんじゃが
I was planning to play Rhythm Heaven, but...
キャプボ、キャプチャーボードというSwitchの画面を
My capture card, the device that captures the Switch screen...
配信に移す機械が、なぜか不調で
...and sends it to the stream, is malfunctioning for some reason.
不調で、映らなくて
It's malfunctioning and won't display.
いろんな人に聞いたので、聞いたのですが
I asked various people about it...
うん、いろんな人がいろんな対処法を教えてくれたんじゃが
Yes, they gave me all kinds of suggestions on how to fix it, but...
なんか1時間ぐらいやっても難しくて
even after trying for about an hour, it was too difficult,
ゲームを変更しましたのじゃ。
so I changed the game-noja.
「さっき最初から外すって言ってた」
'You said earlier you'd remove it from the start.'
確かに！
That's true!
忘れてたのじゃ、忘れてたのじゃ！本当にごめんなのじゃ、忘れてたのじゃ！
I forgot-noja, I forgot-noja! I'm really sorry-noja, I forgot-noja!
さっき言ったことを忘れてたのじゃ。
I forgot what I just said-noja.
ので、リズム天国は
So, Rhythm Heaven...
リズム天国は、またの、
Rhythm Heaven will be played another...
なんか、詳しい人に相談をさせていただいて
I'll consult with someone who knows about this...
治すので、治したら遊びたいと思っておるのじゃ。
...to fix it, and once it's fixed, I'd love to play it-noja.
ので、
So...
今日は、ジオゲッサーで遊ぶのじゃ！
Today, we're playing GeoGuessr-noja!
ジオゲッサー
GeoGuessr...
お主ら知ってる？
Do you guys know it?
お主らは...
Do you guys...
ジオゲッサーというゲーム、噛んじゃった
know the game called GeoGuessr... Oops, I stuttered.
ジオゲッサーをご存知かな？
Are you familiar with GeoGuessr?
わしが唯一遊ぶゲーム
It's the only game I play.
唯一遊ぶゲームなのじゃ
The only game I play.
でも デビューの準備で
But because of my debut preparation,
バタバタしてて 最近全然遊んでなかったから
I've been busy and hadn't played it at all lately.
最近全然遊んでなかったから すごい久しぶりに遊ぶのじゃ
Since I hadn't played it lately, it's been a really long time.
ジオゲッサーはどういうゲームかというと
So, what kind of game is GeoGuessr?
なんか 日本... どこでもいいんじゃが
Well, in Japan... anywhere is fine, really...
世界のある場所
but at some place in the world...
世界のある場所に落とされるのじゃ
you get dropped somewhere in the world.
んで 360度見渡すのじゃ
And then, you look around 360 degrees.
ここがどこか当てるゲームなのじゃ
It's a game where you guess where you are.
うん 当てるゲームなのじゃ
Yes, a guessing game.
好きなのじゃ すごい好きなのじゃ
I love it. I really love it.
そう AZKi先輩が
That's right, AZKi-senpai...
めちゃくちゃ遊んでらっしゃるゲーム
plays this game a whole lot.
そう
Yeah.
AZKi先輩ともね いつか絶対遊んでみたい
I definitely want to play with AZKi-senpai someday.
遊んでほしいなって思ってるのじゃ
I really hope she'll play with me.
今日は 日本マップ
Today, I'll be playing...
ジャパンマップで遊ぼうと
on the Japan map...
思っておりますのじゃ
is what I'm thinking.
日本の どこかに落とされて
I'll be dropped somewhere in Japan...
んで 今日本のどこにいるかなっていうのを
and then I'll try to guess where in Japan I am.
当てる 当てようと思うのじゃ
I'll try to guess it.
動かさず 見渡さず 自分の位置を見極める
No moving, no panning, and guessing your location...
それは ノーブーブ... ノーズーム ノーパン という
That is "no move, no zoom, no pan"...
あの 鬼畜モードなのじゃ
which is an extreme mode!
ノーブーブ ノーパンは あの...
No move, no pan is...
もう 何もわかんないのじゃ
like, you can't tell anything at all!
運ゲーなのじゃ あれ
It's a game of pure luck.
うん なのじゃ
Yeah, it really is.
やっていい？ やっていい？
Should we start? Can I start?
そう 今日さ 今日さ 昨日もさ
Right, so today... today... yesterday too...
昨日の配信見ててくれたお主らならさ
For those who watched yesterday's stream,
わかると思うんじゃが
I think you'll understand, but...
あの 何じゃっけ？
uh, what was it?
あの...
Uhm...
カクカクしてたじゃろ？ わしがカクカクしてたじゃろ？
It was laggy, right? I was lagging, right?
そう なんか... あっ 遊び回りたいの話になってる
Right, like... Oh, wait, the topic on screen is "Asbimaritai".
ちょ ちょ ちょ ちょ タイトル
Wait, wait, wait, the title...
前...
Before...
前... 前話とかにするのじゃ
Let's change it to "Intro" or something.
なんか 機材トラブルがめちゃくちゃ多くて
There have been so many technical issues,
ご迷惑をおかけしておりますのじゃ
and I apologize for the trouble.
頑張って 頑張って
I'll do my best, do my best...
慣れるのじゃ
to get used to it!
わしも早くベテランVTuberになって
I want to become an experienced VTuber quickly,
あんまり機材トラブルが起きないようにしたいと思っておりますのじゃ
so that technical issues don't happen so often.
今日は 頑張りますのじゃ
I'll do my best today!
じゃあ 移動します
Alright, let's switch over!
よいしょー！
Here we go!
あっ ミュートしてた よいしょ
Ah, I was muted. There we go.
聞こえてるのじゃ？
Can you hear me?
聞こえてるのじゃ？ よいしょ
Can you hear me? Okay...
うん
Yeah.
どうかな？ これぐらい...
How's that? Around this...
ん？
Hmm?
これぐらい
Around this much?
これぐらいかな
I guess this is about right.
よし
Alright.
よし できた できたと思うのじゃ
Okay, it's done! I think we're good.
じゃあ 遊んでいくのじゃ
Now then, let's play!
何で何で遊ぶのがいいかの？
What mode should we play?
何で遊ぶのがいいかの？
なんか色んなモードがあって
There are several different modes...
あの さっき言ったノームーブ ノーパン ノーズーム とか
like the "no move, no pan, no zoom" I mentioned...
ノームーブとか ムーブとか色んなモードがあるんじゃが
as well as "no move" or "move" modes.
あと時間 時間とかも 決められるのじゃ
Also, you can set a time limit.
好きな時間で できるんじゃが
You can set it to any time you want...
何分？ まずは普通に
How many minutes? Let's start normally.
普通ってどれぐらいかの？
How long is a normal round?
普通ってやっぱタイムリミットなし？ 5分とか？
Is normal no time limit? Or maybe 5 minutes?
どれぐらい時間設定どれぐらいがいいかの？
How long should the time setting be?
5分？
5 minutes?
まず普通に5分くらい？ ムーブで5分くらい 了解なのじゃ
First, normal 5 minutes? With move, 5 minutes. Got it.
ムーブあんまやったことないのじゃ 酔っちゃうから よいしょ
I don't play "move" often because I get motion sick. Okay...
やってみるのじゃ
Let's try it.
基本設定 基本設定ムーブの5分で
Basic settings... Basic settings: move, 5 minutes.
そう 制限ないとね
Yeah, without a limit...
ジオゲッサーって制限ないとね 山
If there's no limit on GeoGuessr, if you get dropped in a mountain...
山奥とかに落とされるとね
in the deep mountains...
もう本当に 本当に1時間とかかかっちゃうこともあるから
it can honestly take like a whole hour.
じゃあ 早速やってみますのじゃ 日本マップ
So, let's jump right in. Japan map!
ぷっ。あれ？BGMがのってる
Pff. Huh? The BGM is playing.
BGM聞こえとる？
Can you hear the BGM?
BGMうるさいかの？どうじゃ？
Is it too loud? How is it?
おいしょ
Alright...
BGMどう？
How's the BGM?
あきる、あきる野市。あきる野市なんか聞いたことあるのじゃ
Akiruno... Akiruno City. I think I've heard that name.
なんか、ちょっと待って。ちっちゃい
Wait a second. It's too small.
なんか、この辺だった気がするのじゃ。千葉とか、なんかこっち...
I feel like it was around here. Chiba or somewhere around...
えっと、これが
Uh, this is...
多分
probably...
東京電力
Tokyo Electric Power Company (TEPCO)...
うるさくない？ちょうどいい？
Is it too loud? Or just right?
大きい？
Is it loud?
ちょっと大きい？
A little loud?
ちょっと大きい。BGM2つ...
A little loud. There are two BGMs...
あ、切れた？
Oh, did it stop?
BGM切れた？
Did the BGM stop?
どうじゃ？
How is it?
なんか東京電力なのは分かったから
Well, I know it's Tokyo Electric Power, so...
電話番号とか見るのじゃ。042
Let's check the phone number. 042...
えっと
Let's see...
042ってどの辺じゃったかな？
Where was 042 again?
すごい山だね
It's really deep in the mountains.
すごい山の中なのじゃ
It's right in the middle of some deep mountains.
BGM下げてほしい？了解なのじゃ
Do you want me to turn down the BGM? Got it.
どう？
How's this?
下がってる？
Is it lower?
BGM下がってる？
Is the BGM quieter?
いい感じ？
Is it good?
どうじゃ？音量はいい感じ？
How about now? Is the volume okay?
なんか、その...
So, like...
市とかは、まだ全然分かんなくて
I don't know the city at all yet.
よいしょ
Alright...
あの、都道府県は分かるのじゃ
Well, I know the prefecture.
都道府県は分かって
I know the prefecture, but...
市は知ってるのと知ら...
as for the city, whether I know it or don't...
知ら...ほぼ知らない？配信BGMの方がいい？
Don't... You barely know it? Is the stream's BGM better?
じゃあ...
Then...
どう？
How's this?
How is it?
これでいい？
Is this fine?
BGM欲しい？
Do you want BGM?
あと3分しかない？確かに
Only 3 minutes left? You're right.
ちょっ、川、川があるのじゃ
Wait, there's a river.
でも結構読みづらいな。読みづらいな
But it's pretty hard to read. Hard to read.
き、きぬ、きわだ、きわだ台...きわだ...
Ki... Kinu... Kiwada... Kiwadadai... Kiwada...
あきる野市でも、結構山の中じゃから
Even if it's Akiruno City, we're pretty deep in the mountains.
うん、山の中じゃから
Yeah, since it's in the mountains...
なんか、あきる野市の中でも結構奥々いっちゃっていい気がしていて
I feel like we can go really, really far into Akiruno City.
きわだ、なんて書いてあるんじゃろ？
Kiwada... What does it say?
他にあの辺に書いてないかの？
Is there anything else written around there?
おいしょ
Let's see...
よいしょ
Alright...
よいしょ、よいしょ
Okay, okay.
ひ、ひ、ひしざわ？
Hi... Hi... Hishizawa?
川は大きくないのじゃ
The river isn't very big.
よいしょ
Alright...
Okay...
ちょっと今...
Right now...
よいしょ、よいしょ
Okay, okay...
ど、どあせり、ど緊張
I'm super panicked and super nervous!
川の名前？
The river's name?
どあせりど緊張してる。川の名前が...
I'm super panicked and super nervous. But the river's name...
どっかにあるかの？
Is it written somewhere?
めっちゃ山の中なのじゃ
We're really deep in the mountains.
ウェーブする、めっちゃひしざわっていう文字を見る
But I keep seeing the name 'Hishizawa'.
西多摩
Nishitama...
うーん、こっち方面かのじゃ
Hmm, is it this way?
西多摩であきる野市
Nishitama and Akiruno City...
こっち側かの？
Is it on this side?
え、ど緊張してる
Ah, I'm so nervous.
なんかこの辺のどっかの町とかでもおかしくなさそうじゃが
It wouldn't be surprising if it were around one of these towns, but...
静かに結構山の中な気がするんじゃよね
But I really feel like it's deep in the mountains.
看板あった？
Was there a sign?
うーん、この辺、こっち方面な気がするのじゃ
Hmm, I feel like it's around here, in this direction.
進むのじゃ
Let's move forward.
わしが住んでた山とは違うのじゃ
It's different from the mountain I used to live on.
民宿
Minshuku (inn)......
もっと奥多摩辺り？確かに
Further towards Okutama? You're right.
なんか書いてある
There's something written.
大岳清流
Mt. Ootake clear stream...
こういう名前の山がありそう。大岳
There's probably a mountain with that name. Mt. Ootake...
清流
Clear stream.
この辺にありそうな気がするのじゃ
I feel like it would be around here.
ないのじゃ
It's not there.
初見でど山に落とされたのじゃ
Dropped right in the middle of the mountains on my first try.
わしが山住んでるからかな？
Maybe because I live on a mountain?
ちょ、一旦この辺に...あ、あった。大岳山...
Wait, let me look around here... Ah, there it is! Mt. Ootake.
この辺の
Around here...
どっか。この
Somewhere around here.
この辺のどっか...
Somewhere around here...
もっとこっちだったのじゃ。
It was more this way.
なんて読むのじゃ？
How do you read this?
よー...
Yo...
さわフィッシュグランド？
...sawa Fish Ground?
難しいのじゃ！
This is hard!
山暮らしへの配慮。
Consideration for mountain life.
釣りは釣り堀でしかしたことないのじゃ。
I've only ever fished at a fishing pond.
ちょっと山の中難しかったの。
The mountains were a bit hard.
でもこの多分、これなんて読むのじゃ？
But this is probably... how do you read this?
大岳山？
Mount Otake?
この山が多分合って、その近く。
This mountain is probably correct, and near it...
あと西多摩ってのが見えたからこっちの方なのと、
Also, I saw "Nishitama", so it's this way,
秋川の近く...くらい。
and near Akigawa... I think.
むずいのじゃ。
It's hard.
次行くのじゃ。
Let's move on.
山じゃないところに落としてほしいのじゃ。
I want to be dropped somewhere that isn't a mountain.
山じゃないところに
If you dropped me somewhere
落としてくれたら...
that isn't a mountain...
嬉しいのじゃ。
I'd be happy.
関西電力だからこの辺のどっかなのじゃ。
It says Kansai Electric Power, so it's somewhere around here.
えっと、落とした時に
Um, when I was dropped,
山が...
the mountain...
南にない。
Is not to the south.
南に山がないのじゃ。
There is no mountain to the south.
んで北の方にはちょっぴり。
And there's a little bit to the north.
ほいよ。
There we go.
進んでみますのじゃ。
Let's move forward.
何県かのう？
Which prefecture is this?
稲尾...
"Inao"...
稲尾。
"Inao".
めっちゃ田んぼなのじゃ。
It's full of rice fields.
でもね、田んぼってね、日本のどこにでもありますからね。
But you know, rice fields are anywhere in Japan.
日本のどこにでも田んぼってありますからね。
Rice fields are literally anywhere in Japan.
うーわ、あり、むずいのじゃ。
Oh wow, this is hard.
この辺に書いてある。
It's written around here.
あー、兵庫なのじゃ。
Oh, it's Hyogo.
加東市...
Kato City...
の...
of...
確かに、この辺、この辺めっちゃため池多いのじゃ。
True, there are a lot of ponds around here.
加東市。
Kato City.
川のひ、東のとこ、稲尾。
The east of the river, Inao.
加東市稲尾。
Inao, Kato City.
稲尾...
Inao...
田んぼめっちゃあるからかな？
Is it because there are so many rice fields?
田んぼめっちゃあるから稲尾なのかな？
Is it named Inao because there are so many rice fields?
うわー、稲尾探すの難そう。もうちょいヒント欲しいな。
Finding Inao seems hard. I want more hints.
もうちょい広く取りたいけど。
I want to search a bit wider.
うーんと...
Let's see...
むずいかな。
Is it hard?
地区が...「稲尾地区」。
The district is... "Inao District".
稲尾...
Inao...
稲尾を探していくのじゃ。これ探していくの苦手。
I'll search for Inao. I'm bad at searching like this.
苦手じゃから、山とか見たいけど... NW
I'm bad at it, so I want to see mountains, but... NW.
見たいけど、ちょっと多いのじゃ、この辺は。
I want to see them, but there are a bit too many in this area.
よいしょ。建物がある。
Up we go. There's a building.
あとはなんかヒントあるかな？
Are there any other hints?
あんまないのじゃ。
Not really.
ため池、稲尾...
Ponds, Inao...
ため池多いし、田んぼ多い。
Lots of ponds, lots of rice fields.
田んぼも多いのじゃ。
So many rice fields too.
もうちょい大きくしないと見えないかな。
Maybe I won't see it unless I zoom in more.
このサイズでも見えそうだけど。
Should be visible at this size though.
稲尾。
Inao.
稲尾どこ？稲尾出てきてほしいのじゃ！
Where is Inao? I want Inao to show up!
稲尾！
Inao!
ちょ、もうちょいヒント欲しいか。
Wait, do I want more hints?
もうちょいヒント触りたいか。
Do I want to find more hints?
ちょっと進みたいとは思うんじゃが。
I do want to move forward a bit, but...
なんかね、あんま情報がね、なさそうじゃからね。
It seems like there isn't much information,
その、道路番号とかは。
like road numbers.
あ、ミスった方進んじゃった。多分。
Ah, I went the wrong way. Probably.
なさそうじゃから、家。
Since there doesn't seem to be any, a house?
うーん。
Hmm.
稲尾！
Inao!
ね、山がある。
See, there are mountains.
加東市。
Kato City.
ほ、播磨エ...なんか、そういう情報しかないな。
Ha, Harima E... I only have that kind of info.
稲尾！
Inao!
もっと情報が...
More info...
「稲尾分団」。
"Inao Branch".
なんか稲尾以外の稲尾っぽい文字情報がいただけると...
If I could get some text info other than "Inao" that's related to Inao...
でも「稲尾」って立ってるってことは、何かとの間な気がする。
But the fact that "Inao" is standing there makes me think it's between things.
何かと何かの狭まな気がするのじゃ、こういうね。
I feel like it's the gap between something and something, like this.
こういうなんか点点点の間な気もしているのじゃ。
I also feel like it's between these dot-dot-dots.
稲尾、稲尾。
Inao, Inao.
ないの。
There isn't any.
5分あると無限じゃの。5分ってめっちゃ長い。
5 minutes feels like an eternity. 5 minutes is super long.
5分あったら「大沼」...
If I have 5 minutes, I can do "Onuma"...
「大沼」できるのじゃ。
"Onuma".
大沼できますのじゃ。
I can do Onuma.
家がない。
There are no houses.
家少なめの気もするんじゃがな。
I feel like there are very few houses.
地区、地区、地区、地区。
District, district, district, district.
こっち側の山しか見えないから、こっち側な気はするんじゃが。
I can only see the mountains on this side, so I feel like it's around here.
稲生
Inao.
ないのじゃ、5分長くない？5分長いのじゃ！
There's nothing. Isn't 5 minutes too long? 5 minutes is too long!
よいしょ
Alright...
ない。探しま、探そうじゃ！
Nothing. Let's start... Let's start searching!
こういう時って、歩き回った方がいいのか。
In times like this, is it better to walk around?
歩き回った方がいいのか。
Is it better to walk around...
歩き回った方がいいのか、それとも、
...or is it better to...
なんじゃ？
...what?
こっちで探し回った方がいいのか、どっちなんじゃろう？
Is it better to search around here? Which is better?
普段は1分No Moveしかやらんのじゃ。
Normally, I only play 1-minute No Move.
だからなんかその、細かいとこまであんまり行かない、最後まであんまり行かないのじゃ。
So I don't really go into details or search all the way to the end.
え？近くてワロタ。
What? It's so close, lol.
稲生。本当だ！ねえ、稲生あったのじゃ！
Inao. It's true! Inao was actually there!
稲生あったのじゃ！
Inao was actually there!
なんか多いとこに稲生あったのじゃ。
Inao was in a place with a lot of pond things.
確かに。え、意外と道路ある。
True. Oh, there are surprisingly many roads.
意外と道路ある。
There are surprisingly many roads.
ここまで歩いたら道路番号が見えそう。
If I walk up to here, I might see a road number.
おしゃべりもしたいから、
Since I also want to chat,
なるほどなのじゃ。稲生ここにあいましたのじゃ。
I see. So Inao was right here.
画面に映ってたかもしれないじゃ。画面に映ってたのに、見落、見逃しそうに
It might have been on the screen. Even though it was on screen, I almost...
なっていた可能性あり。
...almost missed it.
お水飲む。
I'll drink some water.
次行くのじゃ！
Let's go to the next one!
わしも賢くゲスしたいのじゃ！
I want to make a smart guess too!
わしも賢く、
I also want to smartly...
ね、かっこよくね。
...you know, make a cool guess.
え？山見える、SW。
Oh? I can see mountains to the southwest.
北海道な気がするのじゃ、北海道で。ちょっと見やすい
I feel like it's Hokkaido. In Hokkaido... Let's look for an easy-to-see...
電柱を見たいんじゃが、
...utility pole, but...
北海道ではあるんじゃが、
It is Hokkaido, but...
えっと、
Let's see...
いや、無電柱化高速ってわけでもないのじゃ。
No, it's not like the utility poles are underground either.
あの、あんまりその、最後まで、
Well, not really to the end...
新光一丁目18
Shinko 1-chome, 18.
ちょっと北海道のどこかが知りたいんじゃが、
I want to know where in Hokkaido this is, but...
電柱がちゃんと見える場所が、ポジショニングが取れないのじゃ。
...I can't get into a position to see the utility pole clearly.
見えないの。ちょっと移動するのじゃ。
I can't see it. I'll move a bit.
北海道ではわ、確定で、えっと、
Hokkaido is definitely confirmed, and...
なんじゃが。
...let's see.
わしが被ってる？
Am I blocking it?
よいしょ、ちょっとちっちゃくなるのじゃ。
Alright, I'll shrink myself a bit.
ふんふん。あ、なんか書いてある。市が書いてある。
Hmm... Oh, there's something written there. It says the city.
見るのじゃ。市じゃなかったのじゃ！
Let's see. It wasn't the city name!
残念。市だと思ったんじゃがの。
Too bad. I thought it was the city name.
なんで分かったかというと、電柱が北海道の電柱じゃし、
The reason I knew is that the utility poles are Hokkaido style,
さっき言った最初の地点に41番だからやっぱ札幌の近くなんじゃ。
...and since the first spot had number 41, it must be near Sapporo.
ここの番号で分かるのじゃ。
I can tell by the number here.
そっから、でも結構山が見えたから、
From there, though, I could see quite a few mountains, so...
ちょっと最初のとこ戻るのじゃ。
Let's go back to the starting point.
山がね、結構ね、SW、こっちに、
The mountains, you see, to the southwest, over here...
たぶんこの山な気がする、こっちの方な気がする。違うかな？
...I feel like it's this mountain, on this side. Or maybe not?
この山脈な気がする。でっかい山、山が見えたから、SW。
I feel like it's this mountain range. Since I saw big mountains to the southwest.
で、
And then,
市街地からは外れてる、外れてるから、
Since we are away from the urban area,
どうじゃろうな、これ。
...how about this?
どうなんじゃろう？
How is it?
電柱は全国共通じゃないのじゃ。
Utility poles are not the same nationwide.
あと北海道にしかこの低圧スペーサーみたいなのないのじゃ。
And only Hokkaido has these low-voltage spacers.
あとは、こっからどうしようかな。
Also, what should I do from here?
なんかもうちょい細かい情報が載ってるところが、
If only there was a place with more detailed information...
あるといいんじゃが。うーん。
...that would be great. Hmm...
なにこれ？
What is this?
ゴミ捨て場とか見るか。
Let's check the garbage collection area.
ゴミ捨て場見るか。北海道住宅。
Let's check the garbage area. Hokkaido Housing.
ふんふんふん。
Hmm, hmm, hmm...
朝里団地？
Asari Housing Complex?
朝里団地。
Asari Housing Complex.
あとこの灯油タンクも寒いとこにしかないのじゃ。
Also, these kerosene tanks are only found in cold areas.
うーん。
Hmm...
結構な、結構な山。
Quite a... quite a mountain.
北海道こういう矢羽根めっちゃ多いのじゃ。
Hokkaido has so many of these arrow indicators.
朝里、朝里川公園。
Asari... Asarigawa Park.
朝里
Asari.
市が分かんないのじゃ
I don't know which city this is.
朝光...めっちゃ朝関連のものが出てくるのじゃ
Asamitsu... Lots of things related to "morning" are popping up.
どこ？
Where?
小樽！小樽？
Otaru! Otaru?
確かにこっちもあった、朝里、朝里
Indeed, there was Asari here too. Asari, Asari...
ギリ小樽か
Is it just barely within Otaru?
朝光町？
Asamitsu-cho?
で
And...
新光一丁目の18じゃったから
It was Shinko 1-chome 18, so...
あ、ここ分かりづらいのじゃ、新光一丁目
Ah, it's hard to tell here. Shinko 1-chome...
新光一丁目...一丁目の18
Shinko 1-chome... 1-chome 18.
18が多分ここで
18 is probably here,
18が
and 18 is...
SE、E方向にあるから
located in the SE, E direction, so...
SE...
んで
And then,
グレイスマンション
Grace Mansion.
道の方向は、NE、SW
The direction of the road is NE to SW.
NE、SW
NE to SW.
ここから苦手なのじゃ
I'm bad at this part.
リスポーン
Respawn.
ええと
Let's see...
ここに団地が
There's a housing complex here...
団地あったよね、団地
There was a housing complex here, right?
この辺じゃと思うが、わし苦手んだよな、ここから
I think it's around here, but I'm really bad at...
絞るの
narrowing it down.
ここから絞るの苦手なのじゃ
I'm bad at narrowing it down from here.
どこ？
Where is it?
ここからが分かんないのじゃ
I don't know from this point on.
ここの名前何だっけ？
What was the name of this place?
よいしょ
Here we go.
市営住宅
Municipal housing...
市営住宅...病院これじゃろ？
Municipal housing... This is a hospital, right?
市営住宅...
Municipal housing...
これか
Is it this?
この辺か
Around here?
ん？
Hmm?
市営住宅...惜しいのじゃ！
Municipal housing... So close!
イエス！
Yes!
のじゃ！
Alright!
難しかったのじゃ
That was difficult.
小樽じゃった、こっちだと思ってたけど
It was Otaru! I thought it was over here, though.
南に見えてた山が
The mountain we saw to the south...
余市岳？だった可能性ありなのじゃ
could have been Mount Yoichi.
惜しいのじゃ
So close!
やっぱりいっぱい進んで情報を得るのが大事
As I thought, moving forward a lot to gather information is important.
小樽をなかなか見つけられなかったのじゃ
I couldn't find Otaru easily.
惜しいのじゃ
So close!
次行くのじゃ
Let's move on to the next one.
よいしょ
Here we go.
雪が降りそうなのじゃ
It looks like it's about to snow.
あとは、なんか書いてないかな
And... Is there anything written around here?
鳥取県
Tottori Prefecture.
鳥取県はね、こっち側雪降るからね
It snows on this side of Tottori Prefecture.
鳥取県
Tottori Prefecture...
んー、どっち行くのがいいかの？
Hmm, which way is better to go?
一回こういう時は下るのじゃ
In times like this, it's best to go downhill.
下ってみますのじゃ、よいしょ
I'll try going down. Here we go.
めっちゃ雪降りそうな地域
This area looks like it gets a lot of snow.
川端、これは会社名かな
Kawabata... Is this a company name?
んー
Hmm...
そして、こっち行ってみようか
And, let's try going this way.
よいしょ、進んでみるのじゃ、住宅住宅
Here we go, let's move forward. Houses, houses...
住宅なのじゃ、何で雪降りそうだと思ったかというと、
It's a residential area. Why did I think it would snow...
こういうポールが立ってるところは雪がここまで積もるとこな気がするのじゃ
Because these poles usually indicate snow accumulates up to here.
雪が積もった時も駐車場がどこか分かるように、多分ポールが立ってるはずなのじゃ
The poles are probably there so you can tell where the parking lot is even when snow piles up.
よいしょ
Here we go.
んー、住宅街
Hmm, a residential area.
進むのじゃ、あ、どっちから来たか分かんなくなっちゃった、こっち？
Let's go forward... Ah, I forgot which way I came from. This way?
こっち？こっちか、あ、道っぽいのに出た
This way? This way. Ah, I came out onto a main road.
なんか町の名前が、書いてない、鳥取県
Is there a town name...? It's not written. Tottori Prefecture.
鳥取県なのじゃ、鳥取県で
It's Tottori Prefecture. In Tottori Prefecture,
W方向に、これは、ちょっとした山、ここの高度高そう、高度高そうに見えるのじゃ、S, E, E, こっちも山
to the west is a small mountain... The elevation here seems high. It looks high. To the SE and E are also mountains.
鳥取の...あ、でも道路番号あるのじゃ
In Tottori... Oh, there's a road number.
県道52
Prefectural Road 52.
江府町？江府町？
Kofu-cho? Kofu-cho?
江府町って何？江府町...
What is Kofu-cho? Kofu-cho...
県道52を探すのじゃ！これ探すのめっちゃ苦手なのじゃ
Let's search for Prefectural Road 52! I'm really bad at finding these.
わし道探すのめっちゃ苦手なのじゃ、道路
I'm really bad at searching for roads on the map.
江府町を探すのじゃ
Let's look for Kofu-cho.
52, 52
道路番号じゃ分かんないのじゃ
I can't tell just by road numbers.
道路番号から探すのすごい苦手なのじゃ
I'm really bad at searching using road numbers.
どこじゃろ？江府町あった！江府町吉原、あった
Where is it? Kofu-cho! I found Kofu-cho Yoshihara!
吉、吉原かな？
Yoshi... Yoshihara?
52がここなのじゃ
So 52 is here.
んで
And...
よし
Alright.
ってことはでも 結構住宅 住宅寄り？
But still, it's pretty residential, on the residential side?
うん そして
Yeah, and then...
田んぼ 田んぼ
Rice fields, rice fields.
なんか建物ちゃんとね 見つけたい
I want to find a proper building, you know?
なんか 道を探すより文字探す方が多分得意
I'm probably better at looking for letters than looking for roads.
こっちはあんまりなさそうじゃから 家がいっぱいある方行くのじゃ
There doesn't seem to be much this way, so let's go where there are lots of houses.
よいしょ よいしょ
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
他になんかヒント欲しいな
I want some other clues.
ヒント欲しいな
I want some clues.
なんか 建造物 建造物とかください
Please give me some... buildings, some landmarks.
建造物 でっかい建造物くださいなのじゃ あ、なんかあった
Give me a building, a big building please. Oh, there's something.
あ、ここもしかして 街と街の境目？
Oh, is this perhaps the border between towns?
江府町？ ちょっと見えない
Kofu Town? I can't quite see it.
伯 伯 伯耆町 伯耆町？ 何町？
Hō... Hōki, Hōki Town? Which town?
ここの間 こことここの間じゃから
Between here. Since it's between here and here...
この辺？
Around here?
江府町と これ伯耆… 間 間なのじゃ
Between Kofu Town and Hōki... It's in between them.
間じゃから ここのどっかだと思う
Since it's in between, I think it's somewhere here.
こっちの方な気がする こっち寄りな気がする
I feel like it's this way. It feels closer to here.
でも電車なかったから こっからここまでのどっかの境目なんじゃが
But there was no train, so it's some border from here to here...
やっぱ高度はめちゃくちゃ高そう
The altitude seems really high, after all.
高度はめちゃくちゃ高そうなんじゃ
The altitude seems really high.
52 52 52はこれ
52, 52, 52 is this one.
この辺なのじゃ 52
It's around here, 52.
んで 初期地点どこじゃったかな
And where was the starting point?
あ、結構くねくねしてるとこ
Oh, a place that's pretty winding.
結構くねくねめなところ
A rather winding place.
前… これ前谷川？ これ前谷川なんじゃ
Maetani... Is this Maetani River? It's Maetani River.
結構くねくねめの奥の方から来たから この辺置いちゃうか
I came from way back in the winding part, so should I place it around here?
うん もう18秒しかない
Yeah, only 18 seconds left.
鳥取 うん
Tottori, yeah.
初めの写真のとこ えー N… 3本道じゃから
The starting photo spot... Uh, N... It's a three-way junction...
どこじゃろうな 分かんないのじゃ
Where could it be? I don't know.
えっと この辺じゃない？
Let's see, isn't it around here?
きたのじゃーー！
I got it!
ゲスなのじゃーー！
Perfect guess!
52 県道52号の近くの
52, near Prefectural Road 52...
北がこっち向きで こういう道の形のところを探したのじゃ
The north is facing this way, and I looked for a place with this road shape.
やったのじゃーー！
I did it!
でも5K取れたけど 6mじゃったのじゃ
Even though I got 5K, it was 6 meters off.
やったのじゃーー！
I did it!
次行くのじゃ よいしょ
Moving on to the next one, heave-ho.
小林町 これは中部電力なのじゃ
Kobayashi Town. This is Chubu Electric Power.
小林町
Kobayashi Town.
ふむふむふむ どっち進もうかな こっちになんか看板がある
Hmm, hmm, hmm. Which way should I go? There's some sign over here.
小林町
Kobayashi Town.
あ、青看板見っけなのじゃ
Oh, I found a blue sign!
鹿間 国道1号
Shikama, Route 1.
しかま しかま
Shikama, Shikama.
しかまなんか聞いたことあるような なんか
I feel like I've heard of Shikama somewhere...
何じゃ
What is it?
小林町探すのじゃ えーっと 三重の県道634号
Let's look for Kobayashi Town. Let's see, Mie Prefectural Road 634.
600…
600...
634号 うーーん
Road 634. Hmm...
44 国道44と 600
44, Prefectural Road 44 and 600...
国道から探すのが早いのじゃ 国道探そう 国道どこ？
It's faster to search from the highway. Let's look for Route 1. Where is Route 1?
国道の 4… 国道じゃない 国道1 国道1
Route 4... No, not Route 4, Route 1. Route 1.
44あったのじゃ
Ah, here is 44.
国道
Route 1.
44と634が交差するとこ この辺な気がするのじゃ 632あるし
Where 44 and 634 intersect. I feel like it's around here, since 632 is nearby.
600…
600...
うーーん 634！
Hmm... 634!
634と44が交差するのはこの辺かな？
Is this where 634 and 44 intersect?
小林町！ 小林町きたのじゃ 小林町でリスポーン地点に戻ると
Kobayashi Town! Kobayashi Town is here. If I return to the spawn point from Kobayashi Town...
よし どっから来たっけ？
Alright, where did I come from?
小林町…
Kobayashi Town...
お、こっち行ったっけ？
Oh, did I go this way?
うん。
Yeah.
小林町の、よいしょ。よいしょ。
Kobayashicho... Here we go.
あ、さっきどうやって、どの道から来たのか忘れちゃったのじゃ。
Ah, I forgot which road I just came from.
よいしょ。記憶力がね、全然ないからな。
Here we go. I have no memory at all.
なんか住所とか書いてくれてたらいいんじゃが。小林町自治会？
I wish there was an address written. Kobayashicho Neighborhood Association?
小林町自治会。でも小林町って書いてたからきっとこの辺のどっかな気がしているのじゃ。
Neighborhood Association. But since it said Kobayashicho, I feel like it's somewhere around here.
え、国道何号と何号？634と44が交わるところに行っていて、のじゃ。
Let's see, which routes? Route 634 and 44 intersection... I went there...
こっち行ったっけ？
Did I go this way?
エヌ...こっち行った気がする。最初。
North... I feel like I went this way at first.
小林町しか書いてないのじゃ。
It only says Kobayashicho.
小山田総合医療福祉センターが近くにあるっぽいのじゃ。それ探すか。
Oyamada Comprehensive Medical and Welfare Center seems to be nearby. Shall I look for that?
どこ？ないのじゃ。
Where is it? Not there.
あ、ここのを見たのか。
Ah, did I see this one?
そ、そこは...あれ？どこ行った？どこ行ったどこ行った？
Th-There... Huh? Where did it go? Where did it go?
さっき青看...これ、この青看を
The blue sign just now... this blue sign,
多分さっき見て、これを、ん？違う！
I probably saw it earlier, and... Huh? No!
違うやつなのじゃ。44、634。
It's a different one. 44 and 634.
違うののじゃ。まあここで合わせるか。44、634。
It's different. Well, let's match it here. 44, 634.
44、634で、どっちから来た？わし。
Route 44 and 634... Which way did I come from?
それが分かんないのじゃ。どっちから来たか分かんないのじゃ。でもこれが裏に見えたのじゃ。
I don't know. I don't know which way I came from. But I saw this on the back.
本当に苦手なのじゃ、そういうの！本当にそういうの苦手なのじゃ！
I'm really bad at this kind of thing! Really bad at this!
方角苦手なのじゃ！
I'm bad with directions!
方角がめちゃくちゃ苦手...方角自信なしなのじゃ。
I'm super bad with directions... No confidence in directions.
えーっと、エヌ...Nに進んだ。え？むずい！
Let's see... N... I went North. Eh? This is hard!
ねえ、沼ったのじゃ！助けて、お主ら！分かんなくなっちゃった！
Hey, I'm stuck! Help me, guys! I don't know anymore!
分かんなくなっちゃったのじゃ！迷子になっちゃった！
I don't know anymore! I'm completely lost!
ちょ、好きな方向進んでみるか、一旦ね。
Let's just go in any direction for now.
あー、また違う道が現れた。
Ah, another different road appeared.
また違う道が...ねえ、住所、住所おうちに書いて！おうちに住所書いてほしいのじゃ！
Another different road... Hey, write the address on the house! I want the address written on the house!
どこなのじゃ？
Where is this?!
にゃい！にゃいです！
No! There's nothing!
よいしょ。もう一回行くか。よいしょ。
Okay. Let's go again. Here we go.
これね！これが今見た、え、あ！あれ？戻ってきた！
This is it! What I just saw... Eh, ah! Huh? I'm back!
ここ、国道1号。戻ってきたのじゃ。ここ、ここ。
Route 1 here. I came back. Here, here.
ここね。ここね。
This place. This place.
戻ってきた。え、戻ってきた？なんで戻ってくるのじゃ？何が起きているのじゃ？
I came back. Eh, back? Why did I come back? What is happening?
駐車場。今見えてるのがきっとこれなのじゃ、駐車場。
A parking lot. What I see now must be this parking lot.
そして44、いちと44。
And then 44... 1 and 44.
あ、やばい。ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっ。ちょ、分かんないから、分かんないから、一旦なんかいい感じの住宅地にさすのじゃ。ちょ、分かんない、この辺。
Ah, oh no. Wait, wait, wait. Since I don't know, since I don't know, I'll just guess around some nice residential area. I don't know, maybe around here.
こんな広くなかった。こっちいっちゃった！
It wasn't this wide. I went this way!
した？南だった！南だったのじゃ！北の方行っちゃった。
Under? It was South! It was South! I went towards North.
方角めっちゃ苦手！
I'm so bad with directions!
どっから来たか逆算...ちょっとそれやるのじゃ。次それやるのじゃ。
Tracing back from where I came... I'll do that. I'll do that next time.
なんか、この細かいのがすごい苦手。
I'm really bad at these detailed things.
クスリのアオキ、クスリのアオキ見てなかったのじゃ。
Kusuri no Aoki... I didn't see Kusuri no Aoki.
残念でした。
Too bad.
なんか時間が長ければ長いほどむずいのじゃ。
The longer the time limit, the harder it is.
5分、ゲスしたのじゃ。北に向かってた。
I made my guess with 5 minutes. I was heading North.
なんかどっちの方角...わし、地図めっちゃ苦手で、ジオゲッサー好きなんじゃけど、
Which direction... I'm really bad with maps, although I like GeoGuessr.
ジオゲッサー好きなんじゃけど、あの、なんて言うんじゃ？
I like GeoGuessr, but, how should I put it?
普通にリアルで、お外を全然歩けなくて、
In real life, I can't walk outside well at all,
歩くときの地図は読めないのじゃ。なぜなら方角が分かんないのじゃ。
and I can't read maps when walking. Because I don't know directions.
自分が、自分がどっちに進んでるのか分かんなくて。
I don't know which way I'm heading.
このマップは難易度どれくらい？
What's the difficulty of this map?
このマップは難易度というか、その、日本、
It's not so much about the difficulty of this map, but it's the official Japan map,
公式マップで、日本のありとあらゆる場所が収録されていて、
which contains all sorts of places in Japan.
あの、ぽって、ぽって日本のどこかに落とされるマップなのじゃ。
It's a map where you get plopped down somewhere in Japan.
AZKi先輩とかがよくやっていらっしゃるマップは、
The map that AZKi-senpai and others often play
その、例えばホロメン用オリジナルマップみたいな、その、制作したマップなんじゃが、結構ランダム要素が強い。
is, like, an original map made for Holomembers. But this one has a very strong random element.
地図苦手なのじゃ。
I'm bad with maps.
俯瞰で捉える、俯瞰で捉えるが多分できないのじゃ、全然。
Seeing things from a bird's-eye view... I probably can't do that at all.
わかんないのじゃん。
I wouldn't know.
ホロメンマップは ちょっと今使っていいかみたいな...
I'm not sure if I can use the Holomem map right now...
今日そもそも機材トラブルでゲーム変えたから...
Today, I had to change games due to gear trouble anyway,
どのマップ使っていいか ちょっとまだ確認が取れてなくて。
so I haven't been able to confirm which maps I can use yet.
今日は公式の日本のマップでだけで遊ぶつもり。
Today, I'm planning to play on the official Japan map only.
離島も出るのじゃ。離島も出ますのじゃ。
Islands are included too. Yes, remote islands will show up.
山の中に落とされると詰むのじゃ、ガチで。
If I get dropped in the middle of a mountain, I'm seriously done for.
ちょ、一旦、一旦、一旦1分で...
Wait, let's go with... let's go with one minute...
一旦1分で短めでやってもいい？
Is is okay if I do a short, one-minute round first?
なんか、GeoGuessr遊ぶとき、その、画面酔いするタイプ、わし。
You see, when I play GeoGuessr, I'm the type to get motion sickness.
わし、画面酔いするタイプじゃから、
Since I easily get motion sick,
なんて言うんじゃろ。あんま移動しながらみたいなのはやったことないのじゃん。
how should I say it? I've never really played while moving around much.
ちょっと短めで、動かないでやってみようと思うのじゃん。うん。
I think I'll try playing with a shorter limit and without moving around. Yeah.
ま、動かなかったら時間なんでもいいか。時間制限なしで、動かないでやってみようと思うのじゃ。
Well, if I'm not moving, the time doesn't matter. I'll try playing with no time limit, but without moving.
動かないと酔わなくて楽なのじゃ。
If I don't move, I won't get motion sick, which is nice.
動かないと... 047?
If I don't move... 047?
047って千葉だったっけ？千葉だったとかだったような記憶あり。
Is 047 Chiba? I feel like I remember it being Chiba.
千葉県立柏... 柏... 柏がね、たしかね、
Chiba Prefectural Kashiwa... Kashiwa... Kashiwa is, if I recall...
千葉... なんかめっちゃ情報多くない？情報多いのも逆に苦手なのじゃ、わし。
Chiba... Isn't there way too much information? Actually, having too much info makes it harder for me.
逆に情報多いと頭バグるのじゃ。柏陵高等学校。
Too much information breaks my brain instead. Hakuryo High School.
それを探すのじゃ。
I'll search for that.
あー、情報量が多いのじゃ。柏陵。
Ah, there's so much information. Hakuryo...
柏、柏。
Kashiwa, Kashiwa.
どこじゃろ。高校。
Where is it? The high school...
柏陵、かし... はくりょ、かしわ...
Hakuryo... Hakuryo... Kashiwa...
なんじゃ？
Where is it?
広い目で見てもわかんないかな。そもそも北なのか、
Can I not find it even from a wider view? Is it in the north to begin with?
松戸中央、でも自動車学校。逆井駅東口。
Matsudo Chuo... but that's a driving school. Sakasai Station East Exit.
逆井駅あんま関係ないかな、なんじゃろ。
Maybe Sakasai Station is irrelevant? What is this?
うーん、ほかに情報はなさそう。学校で探すしかないの？
Hmm, looks like there's no other info. Do I have to search by school?
学校探すかー。
Searching for a school...
学校探すの難しいのじゃ。ローラー、柏ローラー、でもちょっと時間が...
Searching for a school is hard. Systematic search... Kashiwa search... but the time...
時間がかかりそうだから、ズバッと決めたいんじゃが。
It feels like it'll take too much time, so I want to just make a quick guess...
時間区切っとけばよかったな。
I should have set a time limit.
こういう答えが載ってるやつって、無限に時間使えちゃうからな。
Because when the answer is right in front of you, you can spend infinite time on it.
うーーーーーん...
Hmmmm...
松戸、逆井駅と書いてあった。
Matsudo... It said Sakasai Station.
この辺の間と予想。予想だが、
I guess it's somewhere around here. It's just a guess, but...
ちょ、うーん？沼るからやめるのじゃ！
Wait, hmm? I'm gonna get bogged down, so let's stop here!
逆井があった！逆井駅があった！
There's Sakasai! Sakasai Station is right there!
逆井駅を頼ればよかったのじゃ。
I should have gone by Sakasai Station!
逆井駅自動車学校の表示のところに書いてあった。
It was written on the sign for the Sakasai Station driving school.
なんか、ああいう広告って本物のときと本物じゃないときがある。
You know, those kinds of advertisements are sometimes real and sometimes not.
偽物と思ったら本物だったのじゃ。
I thought it was fake, but it was real.
失礼いたしましたのじゃ。
My apologies.
次いくのじゃ。
Let's go to the next one.
うお！なんじゃ！
Whoa! What is this!
西札内。
Nishi-Satsunai.
なんか、北海道っぽくない？
Doesn't this look like Hokkaido?
なんかめっちゃ北海道っぽいのじゃん。
It looks extremely like Hokkaido.
北海道の、なんか、どの辺じゃろな。
I wonder where in Hokkaido it is.
村道東6線。
Village Road Higashi 6-sen.
なんか、道が開けすぎな気もしつつ、
While it feels like the road is way too wide open,
牧場、牧場あるし。
there's a ranch. There's a ranch here.
ね。
Right?
そっから、村道。
And from there, a village road.
えー、どこかのー。なんか、体感ね、体感ね、
Hmm, I wonder where. Based on my feel, based on my feel...
体感、こういう、こういう、こういうとこな気がするのじゃん。
My gut says it's a place like this, like this, like this.
こういうとこの気がする。村道わし知らないんじゃが。
It feels like this kind of place. Though I don't know the village roads.
西札内。
Nishi-Satsunai.
ちょ、山見るか、一旦。山、山。いや、見づらいな。
Wait, let's look at the mountains for a bit. Mountains, mountains. Ah, it's hard to see.
西に山。
Mountains to the west.
北はなし。
None to the north.
南もなし。うっすら。西に結構ちゃんと山が
None to the south either, maybe slightly. There are pretty distinct mountains to the west.
ある。あるな。西にちゃんと山があるな。
There are. Indeed. There are clearly mountains to the west.
なんか、一旦この辺おくか。よいしょ。
Let's just place it around here for now. There we go.
ま、この、あ、本当だ、書いてある。中札内。書いてあったのじゃん。
Well, around... Oh, look, it's there. Nakasatsunai. It actually was written on the map!
～と思ったのじゃ。
...is what I thought.
こっちでした。もっと南だったのじゃ。
It was here. It was further south.
北海道広いから絞るのむずいのじゃ。
Hokkaido is so vast, it's hard to narrow down.
山の方向とかで分かるのじゃ。確かに。
You can tell by the direction of the mountains. True.
え、めっちゃ山近くない？
Wait, aren't the mountains really close?
日高山脈だったのじゃ、あれ。気づかなかった。
Was that the Hidaka Mountain Range? I didn't notice.
日高山脈。空港が近かったのじゃ。
Hidaka Mountain Range. The airport was close.
次行くのじゃ。よいしょ。
Let's go to the next one. Up we go.
めっちゃ住宅街。
It's so residential.
めっちゃ住宅街なのじゃ。
It's a really residential area.
九州っぽくない？
Doesn't this look like Kyushu?
菊池... 九州なのじゃ。
Kikuchi... It's Kyushu.
菊池市どこだっけ？
Where is Kikuchi City again?
菊池市。
Kikuchi City.
菊池市の...
Kikuchi City's...
これはなんじゃ？
What is this?
八幡宮。車石八幡宮？
Hachiman Shrine. Kurumaishi Hachiman Shrine?
車石八幡宮があるのじゃ。
There's a Kurumaishi Hachiman Shrine.
でも、これはちょっと分からんのじゃ。
But I don't really know this one.
小さすぎる。
It's too small.
市、まあ、菊池...
City... well, Kikuchi...
あとは山、山も見えないなぁ。
And as for mountains, I can't see those either.
熊本、なんか九州電力の電柱こういう形してるのじゃ。
In Kumamoto, the Kyushu Electric utility poles look like this.
でも、結構奥まった所にあってもおかしくないような気もしていて。
But I feel like it wouldn't be surprising if it's tucked away in a remote area.
奥まった所にあってもおかしくない気がしていて。
I feel like it wouldn't be unusual if it was deep inside.
何八幡宮？車石。
What Hachiman Shrine? Kurumaishi.
車石。まあ、見つかんないからこの辺に置くのじゃ。よいしょ。
Kurumaishi. Well, since I can't find it, I'll place it around here. Here goes.
まあ、もうちょい南。
Well, a bit further south.
もうちょい南だったか。
Ah, so it was a bit further south.
でもまあ、本当だ、車石八幡宮って書いてある。書いてあるのじゃ。
Oh look, it really says Kurumaishi Hachiman Shrine. It is written there.
なんか、でも市から山はこれくらいの距離ってのは大体合ってたのじゃ。
But the distance from the city to the mountains was mostly correct.
のじゃ。のじゃ。
Noja. Noja.
電柱で地域、地方大体分かるからお主ら
Since you can mostly tell the region or prefecture from the utility poles, you guys...
あの、写真あげちゃダメだよ。
Um, don't post pictures.
お主ら、散歩中とかに写真あげちゃダメなのじゃ。
You guys shouldn't post pictures while out on walks.
散歩中に写真あげると簡単に特定されちゃうのじゃ。
If you post pictures during a walk, you can easily be located.
ちなみにわしも、ちょっと怖い思いをしたことがあるのじゃ。
By the way, I've had a slightly scary experience myself.
から、気をつけるのじゃ、お主らも。
So, be careful, you guys too.
次行くのじゃ。よいしょ。
Let's go to the next one. Up we go.
あんまり情報がなさそうな予感。
I have a feeling there won't be much information.
なんか、分からないのは本当に分からないのじゃ。
When I don't know, I really don't know.
ふむ、ふむ、ふむ。
Hmm, hmm, hmm.
縦、か。
Vertical, huh?
これわしあんま分かんないのじゃ。
I don't really know this one.
ぼかされてら。ぼかされてるのじゃ。
It's blurred. It's blurred.
何電力？教えてほしいのじゃ！
Which power company? I want you to tell me!
この太いのどこだっけ？忘れちゃったのじゃ。
Where was this thick one from again? I forgot.
え、これわし分かんないかも。
Wait, I might not know this.
これわし分かんないから、このみかんゲスするしか。これみかんなのかな？
I don't know this, so I have to guess by these mikan. Are these mikan?
これ、これみかんなのかな？なんなんじゃ？これなんなんじゃと思う？
Are these really mikan? What are they? What do you think they are?
でもなんか山とかない。こっちにあるか。
But there are no mountains. Are they over here?
南に、南に山があるか。
To the south, is there a mountain to the south?
南に山があるか。
Is there a mountain to the south?
これ全然分かんないのじゃ。分かんないけど、
I have absolutely no idea. I don't know, but...
これなんじゃろ？
What could this be?
でも、窓どうなってこれ？
But how are the windows on this?
分厚く見えてしまう、どうしても。
They look thick to me, no matter what.
分厚めの窓に見えちゃうんじゃが、違うかな？
They look like pretty thick windows, is that wrong?
これは、こういう問題が出たらもう潔く諦めてるのじゃ、分かんないから。
When a problem like this comes up, I just gracefully give up since I don't know.
ちょっと情報がないから、見たいけど。見るだけ見るか？
There's little info, but I want to look. Shall I just look?
見るだけ見るが...
I'll take a look, but...
うーーーん、なんか...
Hmh, somehow...
こういう時は、こういう時は兵庫とかに置くのじゃ。岡山とか。岡山とかに置くのじゃ。
In times like this, I'll place it in Hyogo. Or Okayama. I'll place it in Okayama.
でも結構、ちょい寒そう。これって、なんか二重窓が本当に二重っぽいのか、ただそういうデザインなのかが
But it looks a little cold. I can't tell if these double windows are really double-paned or if it's just the design.
分かんないことがあり。
There are things I don't know.
一旦この辺に置くのじゃ。一旦この辺に置くのじゃ。
I'll put it around here for now. I'll put it around here for now.
名古屋！？
Nagoya!?
中部なんだ！全然分かんなかった！
It's Chubu! I had absolutely no idea!
え、めっちゃ名古屋市！
Wait, it's right in Nagoya City!
ちょっと見ていい？全然分かんなかったのじゃ。稲沢市。
Can I look? I had absolutely no idea. Inazawa City.
え、全然分かんなかったのじゃ。ちょっと動いていい？
Wow, I really had no idea. Can I move around a bit?
本当に分かんなかった。本当に全く分かんなかった。
I really had no idea. Really, absolutely no idea.
本当に分かんなかった。
I really didn't know.
へえー、ここまで来たらね、ここまで来たら見えるんじゃが、
Oh, once we get to here, once we get to here we can see it...
本当に全然分かんなかった。
I really, completely had no idea.
ジオゲッサーはやっぱ一問一答だから
Since GeoGuessr is rapid fire,
次この景色が出たら名古屋ってことにするのじゃ
next time this landscape shows up, I'll assume Nagoya.
次ね
Next one.
よいしょ
Alright.
全然わからなかったのじゃ
I had absolutely no idea!
どこかな
I wonder where this is.
あ、備前
Oh, Bizen.
備前焼き
Bizen ware.
備前？
Bizen?
あーなるほどね
Ah, I see.
あ、書いてあるじゃん。あるじゃん。
Oh, look, there's a sign.
吉備中央。国道。
Kibi Chuo. National Route.
めっちゃ書いてあるのじゃ。
So much information is written here.
71？国道53？吉備中央。
Route 71? National Route 53? Kibi Chuo.
このへんなのじゃ。
So it's around here.
まあなんか中国電力で、でも71。
Well, it's Chugoku Electric Power, but Route 71.
このまま置いちゃうか。53号、71。
Should I just pin it here? Route 53, 71.
こういうの探すの苦手なのじゃ。71。
I'm bad at finding these things. Route 71.
71と、53が交わるところ。
Where Route 71 and 53 intersect.
こっちとか。
Around here?
こういうのわかんないのじゃ。川あるくね？
I don't understand this. Isn't there a river?
よいしょ。旧国名なのじゃ。
Okay. These are the old province names.
山！山がめっちゃ見える、山の中。
Mountains! I see so many mountains. We're in them.
これが国道53号。
This is National Route 53.
うーん...
Hmm...
こっからはわかんないのじゃ、奥。
I don't know beyond this point. It's deep in.
遠かった。こっちでした。こっちでしたのじゃ。
It was far! It was here. It was over here.
うーん。なんか青看板の見方とか、方角とかが全然わからなくて、
Hmm... I don't know how to read the blue signs or directions at all.
全然わからなくて、地図苦手。
I have no idea. I'm bad with maps.
地図苦手じゃから地図以外の情報で見るのじゃ。
Since I'm bad at maps, I look at other clues.
交わるところがあるならちょっと前。確かに！
If there's an intersection, it's a bit back. Indeed!
確かに！
Indeed!
次行くのじゃ、あ、結果を見る。
Next round... Ah, let's look at the results.
2万点。
20,000 points.
一回ちょっと途中でね、ここの、ここのね、
Once, in the middle... over here, you see,
いなさーし？ここで大ミスをしてしまい、
Inasa? I made a huge mistake here,
しましたのじゃ。うん。
and failed. Yeah.
地図がね、わかるようになったらもっと上手になると思うのじゃ。
If I can understand maps, I think I'll get better.
ね、川なかったよね。川なかったなーっていうのは思って。
Right, there was no river. I was thinking about how there was no river.
こんなでっかい川見えなかったよね。そう思うのじゃ。うん。
We couldn't see such a big river. That's what I think. Yeah.
そう、青看板とかは、やっぱアズキ先輩って地理めっちゃ強いから、
Right, when it comes to blue signs, AZKi-senpai is super strong in geography.
そういう地理系の知識とかだと全然、
So when it comes to geography knowledge, I can't...
全然もう勝てません。もうまったく、まったく、
I can't compete at all. I'm absolutely,
まったく相手になりません、わし、弱すぎて。
absolutely no match for her. I'm just too weak.
うん。
Yeah.
名古屋痛恨のミスなのじゃ。
The Nagoya error was a painful mistake.
もう一回するのじゃ。ちょっと、次ちょっと、ちゃんと時間縛ってやるか。
I'll do it one more time. Next time, I'll set a time limit.
時間縛らないと一生できちゃうのじゃ。よいしょ。
If I don't set a time limit, I can play forever. Alright.
もう一回1分でやっていい？
Can I do it with a 1-minute limit again?
ね、道路の太さも違ったよね。
Right, the road width was different too.
そう、地理の勉強もちゃんとしたいのじゃ。
Yes, I really want to study geography properly.
わしまだ都道府県とかしか知らなくて、
I only know the prefectures,
市とかは全然知らないから、
not the cities at all,
市。なんかあんま動画見て勉強とかもそこまでたくさんしてるわけじゃないから、
so... I haven't really studied that much from videos either.
今後ね、アズキ先輩が戦っていただけるって時には、
So in the future, if AZKi-senpai plays with me again,
ちょっと1ヶ月くらい特訓して
I'd like to train for about a month
遊びたいと思いますのじゃ。よいしょ。
and play with her. Alright.
なんか、1人でさ、やってるとさ、
When you play alone, you know,
なんか途中で、もういいかなってなっちゃう。
you kind of feel like, 'Is this enough?' midway through.
人と遊びたいのじゃ、やっぱ。人と遊びたい。
I want to play with people, after all. I want to play with people.
でもなん、定期的にね、帰ってくるけど。
Though I still come back to it periodically.
人と遊びたいから、アズキ先輩が遊んでくれるの嬉しいのじゃ。
I want to play with others, so I'm glad AZKi-senpai plays with me.
南、丘、丘じゃ。
South, hills... It's hilly.
丘なんじゃが、それ以外のことがわかんないのじゃ。
It's hilly, but I don't know anything else.
またドミスの可能性あり。
There's a possibility of another huge mistake.
このポール系は覚えてないのじゃ。
I don't remember this pole style.
どこなのじゃ？教えてほしいのじゃ。
Where is this? I want someone to tell me.
そう、山に住んでた時期長いからね。コーチング、
Right, because I lived in the mountains for a long time.
でもちょっと置くか。1回どこか置くか。
Let me pin it somewhere. I'll just pin it once.
丘、丘がめっちゃあります。
Hills, there are lots of hills.
ド外れの可能性あり。南。
There's a chance I'm way off. South.
ちょ、わからんのじゃ。ド外れなのじゃ！
I don't know. I'm way off!
神奈川でしたのじゃ。神奈川でしたのじゃ。
It was Kanagawa. It was Kanagawa!
神奈川わかった？
You knew it was Kanagawa?
なんで神奈川わかったの？
How did you know it was Kanagawa?
神奈川は分かんなかった。書いてあったかな、どっかに。
I didn't know it was Kanagawa. Was it written somewhere?
白い壁の家って神奈川なの？
Are houses with white walls typical in Kanagawa?
なんか、あんま神奈川感が分かんなかったのじゃ。
I just couldn't get a feel for Kanagawa.
神奈川ってこんな景色なんじゃ。
So this is what Kanagawa looks like.
情報が足りませんでした。
I didn't have enough information.
車のナンバーは、ジオゲッサーはぼかされてて見えませんのじゃ。
License plates are blurred on GeoGuessr, so I can't see them.
よいしょ。次行くのじゃ。
Alright, let's move to the next one.
なんか、こっち辺の香り。
It has the vibe of this area.
よいしょよいしょ。よいしょよいしょ。どこじゃろなぁ。
Up, up. Up, up. Where could this be?
なんか、
Hmm...
よいしょ。
Here we go.
ね、だいたいあんな感じの景色。
Yeah, it's mostly that kind of scenery.
南に山っぽいの見えんのじゃ。
I can see what looks like mountains to the south.
新参和板金。
Shin-Sanwa Sheet Metal...
Shin-Sanwa Sheet Metal.
え、これ、これこっちじゃないの？こっちとかじゃないのじゃ。
Wait, isn't it over here? Maybe somewhere around here?
富山な気がするのじゃ。
I feel like it's Toyama.
富山っぽい。富山っぽい。
Looks like Toyama. Looks like Toyama.
空もなんか曇りっぽいし。
The sky is also kind of cloudy.
でも山とか全然見えないから、ちょっと分からんの。意外と海方面とか、海近とか。
But since I can't see mountains at all, I'm not sure. Maybe near the sea, or towards the coast.
のじゃ。
Let's guess.
んー。高岡市かの？
Hmm. Is it Takaoka City?
富山ではあったけど、
It was Toyama, but...
漢字、漢字苦手なのじゃ。高岡市なのじゃ。板金？板金って読むの？
Kanji, I'm bad at kanji. It is Takaoka City. Sheet metal? Is that read "bankin"?
富山でしたのじゃ。
It was Toyama!
なぜ富山か。
Why did I think Toyama?
なんか、プレート横、全部横だから、
Since the labels on the poles are horizontal...
あの北陸電力だなと思って、なんとなく、なんとなくなのじゃ。
I figured it was Hokuriku Electric Power, just a hunch.
で、あんま山が、富山の南の方だともうちょい山が見えるけど、あんま山が見えなかったから、
Also, since I couldn't see many mountains—you'd see them more in the south of Toyama—
ちょっと海ら辺かなって思ったのじゃ。
I thought it might be closer to the sea.
植生は全然詳しくないのじゃ。植生は、
I don't know anything about the vegetation. Vegetation...
分かんないのじゃ。木が太い細いしか、分かんないのじゃ。
I have no idea. I only know if a tree is thick or thin.
次行くのじゃ。よいしょ。
Moving on to the next one!
うん、うん、うん。
Okay, okay.
ダイレックス。
Direx.
鳥栖？鳥栖ってどこだっけ？
Tosu? Where was Tosu again?
鳥栖ってどこだっけ？鳥栖ってどこだっけ？ちょっと鳥栖って、
Where is Tosu? Where is Tosu? Let me look up Tosu...
いや、九州だ。九州？
No, it's Kyushu. Kyushu?
ん？
Huh?
何が本当なのじゃ？
What is the truth here?
か、か、うにょ、うにょ、うにょ。
Ka, ka... unyo, unyo, unyo...
なん、なんじゃ？なんじゃ？
What? What is that?
九州電力？鳥栖めっちゃ聞いたことあると思うんだけどな。
Kyushu Electric Power? I'm pretty sure I've heard of Tosu a lot.
めっちゃ聞いたことある気がするんじゃが、
I really feel like I've heard of it, but...
鳥栖、鳥栖。
Tosu, Tosu...
加藤田町？
Katodamachi?
加藤田町、加藤田町、
Katodamachi, Katodamachi...
忘れたのじゃ！
I forgot!
探すのじゃ、鳥栖。鳥栖どこだっけな。あった、鳥栖市！
I need to find it, Tosu. Where was Tosu again? Ah, there it is, Tosu City!
鳥栖市。加藤田町。
Tosu City. Katodamachi.
加藤田町。加藤田町まで行けなかったのじゃ。
Katodamachi. I couldn't get all the way to Katodamachi.
この辺だった。ギリギリ！超ギリギリ！
It was around here. So close! Extremely close!
新鳥栖駅。そっか、新幹線通ってるからか。
Shin-Tosu Station. Right, because the Shinkansen runs through here.
なんか、久しぶりにやると地名とかも全部抜け落ちている、のじゃ。
It feels like when you play after a while, you completely forget all the place names.
見るか。よいしょ。加藤田、加藤田町。
Let's see. Here we go. Katoda... Katodamachi.
加藤田町ないの？広げても。どこじゃ？書いてないのじゃ、加藤田町。
Is Katodamachi not showing up even when I zoom in? Where is it? It's not written here.
西九州新幹線。そうそうそうそう。これここに通ってるのじゃ。
West Kyushu Shinkansen. Yes, yes, yes, yes. This runs right through here.
新鳥栖。新鳥栖駅。
Shin-Tosu. Shin-Tosu Station.
市、いっぱい覚えたいな。まだ全部市覚えてないから、いつか全部覚えたいのじゃ。
I want to memorize a lot of cities. I haven't memorized all of them yet, so I want to learn them all someday.
加東市？
Kato City?
次、よいしょ。
Next, here we go.
広め。広い景色。
Wide open. A wide view.
広い景色なのじゃ。
It's a very spacious landscape.
広い空。焦げてるプレート。
Wide sky. A burnt pole plate.
うん。
Hmm.
のじゃ。
Well...
のじゃ？のじゃ？
Huh? What is this?
のじゃぁ。
I see...
何なのじゃ？
What is this place?
九州とかかな。
Is it Kyushu or somewhere?
九州とかかな？
Maybe Kyushu or somewhere?
広い。
It's spacious.
山がある、西に？
There are mountains. To the west?
南にはない。これ何？
None to the south. What is this?
白鳥がいる、白鳥。え、でもなんか…
There are swans, swans. Wait, but...
いや、北海道だ。
No, it's Hokkaido.
北海道なのだろうじゃ。
It must be Hokkaido, then.
北海道のどこかと言われると…え、本当に北海道？
If you ask where in Hokkaido... Wait, is it really Hokkaido?
いや、わかんないのだろうじゃ。
Actually, I have no idea.
西に山…
Mountains to the west...
え、どこじゃろ？
Huh, where is it?
わー！北海道当てられてよかった！
Wow! I'm glad I got Hokkaido right!
北海道当てられてよかった！
I'm so glad I got Hokkaido right!
全然わかんなかったのだろうじゃ。
I had absolutely no idea.
この辺白鳥？へー。
Swans around here? Huh.
ちょっと最初九州押しちゃったけど、北海道だったのだろうじゃ。
I clicked Kyushu at first, but it was Hokkaido.
ちゃんと見てなかったのだろうじゃ。
I didn't look closely enough.
えー、全然わかんなかった。北海道のどこかわかるヒントあったかの？
Eh, I had no idea. Was there a hint pointing to where in Hokkaido?
白鳥ってこの辺なのかな？
Are swans common around here?
白鳥ってこの辺なのかな？あまり詳しくないのだろうじゃ。
Are swans common around here? I'm not very familiar with it.
伊達市？
Date City?
伊達市。
Date City.
あれ、わし動いとる？動いとる。
Wait, am I moving? Yes, I am.
どうやってここの北海道の西、南西に寄せられるんじゃろう。伊達市。
How could I narrow it down to the west, southwest of Hokkaido? Date City.
ここ当てられるヒントあったかの？
Was there any hint to get this right?
まあ、西、山…山、山、山。
Well, west, mountains... Mountain, mountain, mountain.
うーん、ちょっと難しいのだろうじゃ。広いのは北海道。
Hmm, that's a bit difficult. Hokkaido is indeed spacious.
まあ、開けてはいるけど。
Well, it is open, but...
なんかこれめっちゃ北海道っぽい。これめっちゃ北海道っぽいのじゃろうじゃ。
This somehow looks super Hokkaido-like. This is super Hokkaido-like.
で、海沿いだったね。
And it was along the coast.
ちょっと北海道ってわかったのがギリギリだったのだろうじゃ。あまりにも。
Knowing it was Hokkaido was a close call, honestly.
カクカク。カクカク。
Lagging. Lagging.
デッドスペースなくない？
Isn't there any dead space?
あ、あるあるある！あった！あったのだろうじゃ！めちゃ見落としてた！
Oh, there is, there is! There was! There was! I totally missed it!
これで九州行ったのちょっとおもろいのじゃ。ちょっとおもろいのじゃ。動揺。
Going to Kyushu after this is a bit funny. A bit funny. Shaken.
マンホールが伊達市のデザイン？白鳥？
Is the manhole cover a Date City design? A swan?
白鳥だと伊達市なのだろうじゃ？
If it's a swan, is it Date City?
えー、可愛いから覚えよう。
Aw, it's cute, so I'll remember it.
白鳥のマンホールは伊達市のデザインっぽいのじゃろうじゃ。
So a swan manhole is likely a Date City design.
覚えよう、可愛いから。
I'll remember it, since it's cute.
白鳥で有名？あ、有名なんだ。じゃ、わし知らなかったのだろうじゃ。
Famous for swans? Ah, it is. Well, I didn't know.
次は覚えるのだろうじゃ。次覚えて、次白鳥が出たらここに置くのだろうじゃ。
I'll remember it for next time. Next time I see a swan, I'll place it here.
書いてある？ちょ、それ見せてほしい。
Is it written on it? Wait, let me see that.
よしよしよし。
Okay, okay, okay.
本当だ！ここに白鳥の背中に、これ何て読むんだ？
It's true! Here, on the swan's back... what does this say?
あり、ありす？ありじゅ？ありじゅ？
Ari... Arisu? Ariju? Ariju?
ちょ、漢字自信なし。読み仮名教えてほしいのだろうじゃ。
Wait, I'm not confident with kanji. I want you to tell me the reading.
読み仮名教えてほしいのだろうじゃ。ありじゅ、ありじゅ、あんじゅ？何て読むのだろうじゃ？
I want you to tell me the reading. Ariju, ariju, anju? How do you read it?
でも確かに文字書いてあった。気づかなかったのだろうじゃ。
But there were indeed letters written. I didn't notice it.
およ、本当だ。
Oh, it's true.
うす？うすって読むのだろうじゃ？ありす？ありす？ありじゅ？何が本当？うすじゃん！
Usu? Is it read as Usu? Alice? Alice? Ariju? What's real? It's Usu!
あ、うす！あ、これ「うすざん」って読むんだ。有珠山。
Ah, Usu! Ah, you read this as "Usu-zan". Mount Usu.
有珠って読むらしいのだろうじゃ。有珠町。
Apparently it's read as Usu. Usu Town.
有珠町のマンホールは白鳥がいるのだろうじゃ。覚えたのだろうじゃ。
Usu Town's manhole has a swan. I remembered it.
ありがとうなのだろうじゃ。次行くか。
Thank you. Shall we move to the next one?
のじゃ〜 のじゃ〜
Noja~ Noja~
え！ゆめタウンある！西なのだろうじゃ！
Eh! There's a Youme Town! It must be the west!
ゆめタウンあるよ、ゆめタウン！
There's a Youme Town, Youme Town!
ゆめタウンは、西とか南な気がするのだろうじゃ。
I feel like Youme Town is in the west or south.
ゆめ〜
Youme~
えー、どこじゃろうな〜
Eh, where could it be~
そっから、そっから先なんだよな。九州から先。九州から先。でも結構、広めの道がありそう。
From there, it's beyond that. Beyond Kyushu. Beyond Kyushu. But it seems like there are relatively wide roads.
広めの道がありそう。広めの道がありそうだし、こっちの方に置いても怒られない気はする。
It looks like there are wide roads. It feels like there are wide roads, and I wouldn't be scolded for placing it around here.
山とかはちょっと見えないのだろうじゃ。山とかちょっと全然見えない。
I can't really see mountains. I can't see mountains at all.
見えないから何とも言えないんじゃが。
Since I can't see them, I can't really say, but...
マンホールね、わしね、知らん全然。
As for the manholes, I don't know them at all.
もっと北か！北九州！北九州だったのだろうじゃ！
More to the north! Kitakyushu! It was Kitakyushu!
福岡のどこかかなって思ったんじゃが。
I thought it might be somewhere in Fukuoka, but...
とおがちょう？とおがちょう？
Tooga-cho? Tooga-cho? (Onga Town?)
中国地方のが多い？それはそうなのだろうじゃ。中国地方に多いのだろうじゃ。
There are more in the Chugoku region? That's true. There are many in the Chugoku region.
遠賀町
Onga District...
え、これ分かるかな？
Huh, can they tell where this is?
北、北の方に
Towards the north...
海の香りする？
Does it smell like the ocean?
こっちに海の香りする？おぬしら。
Do you guys smell the ocean over here?
結構海近なはずなんじゃが。
It's supposed to be pretty close to the sea.
海の香りしないのじゃ？ちょっと天気がこの日は悪いからかのう？
You don't smell the ocean? Maybe it's because the weather is bad today?
天気が良かったら海の香りしたかの？
If the weather were nice, would it smell like the ocean?
まあ確かに言われてみれば、向こうに海がありますよと言われたら、あるような気も。
Well, indeed, if someone told me there's an ocean over there, I'd feel like it is.
あるような気もしなくもないくらい。
I might feel like it's there, to some extent.
おんが？
Onga?
遠賀町。
Onga Town.
まあ遠賀町聞いたことある気がするのじゃ。
Well, I feel like I've heard of Onga Town before.
遠賀町。
Onga Town.
海の香りする。
It smells like the ocean.
海の香りするのじゃ。
It does smell like the ocean.
なんか不自然に高い建物とか山とかなくて、景色が開けすぎてると、めっちゃ海の香りを感じ取っちゃうのじゃ。遠賀川。
When there are no unnaturally tall buildings or mountains and the view is too open, I really smell the ocean. Onga River.
かっこいいのじゃ、遠賀川。
The Onga River sounds cool.
遠賀川なのじゃ。
It's the Onga River.
ふーん。そういうのがあるんじゃな。
Hmm. So there is such a thing.
最後に、なんか動いたりする？
Lastly, shall we do one where we can move?
ちょ、おぬしら、わしにいつまで付き合ってくれる？
Hey, how long will you guys stay with me?
わしにいつまで付き合ってくれる？
How long will you stay with me?
おぬしらはわしと共に、
Will you all, together with me...
わしと共に、え、これ本物？
Together with me... Wait, is this real?
わしと共に過ごしてくれる？
...spend time with me?
あの、時間制限なしで、時間制限なしでやってみませんか？
Um, with no time limit... Shall we try playing with no time limit?
ちょっと時間制限なしだと、ガチ一生、一生続いちゃうんじゃが。
If we do it with no time limit, it might literally go on forever.
あ、一生続かなそう。ありがたい。
Ah, looks like it won't go on forever. Thank goodness.
ありがたいけど、携帯電話番号は見てもわかんないのじゃ。
Thank goodness, but looking at a mobile number doesn't tell me anything.
市外局番欲しいのじゃ。よいしょ。
I want the area code. Okay.
え、ここ戻るしかできない。
Wait, I can only go back here.
森、森小路二丁目。
Morishoji 2-chome.
何区？
Which ward is this?
でも結構情報量多そうだから期待、期待できる。期待できるのじゃ。
But there seems to be a lot of info, so I can expect a lot. I can look forward to it.
うん。
Yeah.
付き合って。じゃあ、この試合が最後じゃけど、この試合はできるだけいっぱい当てられるように頑張りたいと思っておりますのじゃ。
"Stay with you." Then, this match will be the last, but I want to try my best to get as many right as possible in this round.
おぬしを早く寝かしつけるのじゃ、わしが。
I will make you go to bed early.
よいしょ、それでは、
All right then,
拝見させていただくのじゃ。
let me take a look.
街並みを、
The streetscape...
街並みを、こんな、大阪じゃろ？大阪じゃろ？
The streetscape... This looks like Osaka, right? It's Osaka, right?
と思っているんじゃが。
Or so I think.
大阪だと思っているんじゃが、がんばれ、がんばれ、がんばれ！
I think it's Osaka, but... Come on, hang in there!
がんばれ、がんばれ！がんばれ！
Hang in there! Come on!
がんばれ！
Hang in there!
動く？動ける？
Is it moving? Can I move?
あ、動けた、動けた。よし、よし。
Ah, I can move, I can move. Okay, okay.
ちょっと情報、情報が、情報取りすぎて、画面がカクついてるのじゃ。
It's loading too much information, so the screen is stuttering.
ドカクつき。ドカクつき来た。
Major stuttering. Massive lag is here.
旭区。
Asahi Ward.
通った。ちょっと！
I found it! Wait!
パソコンがんばるのじゃ。
Come on, computer, do your best.
カクカクするのじゃ、カクカクするのじゃ、ちょい。
It's stuttering, it's so laggy. Hold on.
動くか？動くか？動く、動く。
Will it move? Will it move? It's moving, it's moving.
大阪、絶対大阪なのじゃ。で、
Osaka, it's definitely Osaka. And...
旭区、旭区。
Asahi Ward, Asahi Ward.
旭区知らないから探すのじゃ。旭区ってどこじゃろうな。
I don't know Asahi Ward, so I have to search for it. I wonder where Asahi Ward is.
旭区ってどこじゃろう。
I wonder where Asahi Ward is.
旭区、旭区。
Asahi Ward, Asahi Ward.
なんか大阪だと思ったのは、関西電力で道がギュウギュウだったからなのじゃ。
The reason I thought it was Osaka was because the streets were so cramped around Kansai Electric Power's area.
道がギュウギュウだったからなのじゃ。
It's because the streets were so cramped.
旭、旭区、森小路。
Asahi... Asahi Ward, Morishoji.
森小路、二丁目。
Morishoji 2-chome.
森小路。
Morishoji.
難しいのじゃ、この、なんかこういうさ、地図を見てさ、置けない。
It's hard. I can't just look at the map like this and pin it.
わし、地図見て置けないんじゃよ、なんか。
For some reason, I can't pin it just by looking at the map.
でも、どこじゃ？ってなっちゃう。森小路二丁目。
I keep wondering, "Where is it?" Morishoji 2-chome.
一丁目、
1-chome...
二丁目ない。二丁目ないのじゃ。
There's no 2-chome. 2-chome is missing.
一丁目しかない。
There's only 1-chome.
のじゃ。
Huh...
一丁目、
1-chome...
ね、一丁目以外ない。あ、二丁目。
Yeah, nothing other than 1-chome. Ah, 2-chome.
二十一、
21...
二十一？
21?
二十一。
21...
これ苦手。
I'm bad at this.
二十一。二十一。
21. 21.
この辺？
Around here?
違うかも。
Maybe not.
で、リスポーン地に戻るのじゃ。
And let's return to the spawn point.
これ何か書いてあった気がするのじゃ。
I think there was something written on this.
森小路二丁目12
Morishoji 2-chome 12.
森小路二丁目12が、えっと...
Morishoji 2-chome 12 is, let's see...
森小路二丁目12... ここかな？森小路二丁目12...
Morishoji 2-chome 12... Maybe here? Morishoji 2-chome 12...
二丁目...
2-chome...
二丁目のさ、範囲がどこまでかとかがさ、わし全然わかんないんじゃよ。
I have no idea how far 2-chome extends.
二丁目、この辺なのかな？
2-chome... Is it around here?
森小路... こっちなのかな？それとも。
Morishoji... Is it this way? Or...
それがね、よく分かんないのじゃ。
I don't really know that part.
うーん。
Hmm...
どっちが森小路の二丁目なんじゃろ？
Which side is Morishoji 2-chome?
一丁... どこまでが一丁目なんじゃろ？
1-cho... How far does 1-chome go?
こっちが二丁目？
Is this side 2-chome?
でも、道、確かに道から特定するか。
But, the path, let's pinpoint it using the path.
えっと、北を向いたときに、あれ？ここ？ここか？
Let's see, when facing north, huh? Here? Is it here?
いや、道的にここだな。
No, path-wise, it's here.
道的にここなのじゃ。
Path-wise, it's definitely here.
じゃあ、寄せていきますのじゃ。
Then, let's zoom in close.
えーっと、うーん、こっちで、こっちで...
Let's see, hmm, here, here...
こっちで... え、この辺かな？
Here... Huh, around here?
もうちょいこっち？
A bit more this way?
0メートルって難しいのじゃ。
Getting 0 meters is hard.
この辺かな？一旦この辺でいかのじゃ。
Around here? Let's go with this for now.
のじゃー！
Noja!
0メートル無理なのじゃ！
0 meters is impossible!
こっちじゃった。
It was over here.
こっちだったのじゃ。
It was this way.
苦手なのじゃ。
I'm bad at this.
最後のこの0メートルに行くやつ。
This last part of trying to get 0 meters.
ふん。
Hmph.
ちょっとお水飲みたい。
I want to drink some water.
よいしょ。よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ。
Yoisho. Yoisho, yoisho, yoisho.
ゼロエス失敗なのじゃ。
Failed to get 0s.
次。
Next.
よいしょ。
Yoisho.
ふん。なかなかに開けた景色。これ絶対もう...
Hmph. Quite an open landscape. This is definitely already...
これもう、これもうさすがに北海道でいいのじゃ。
This is definitely Hokkaido by now.
さすがに、もうこれは北海道でいいと思いますのじゃ。
As expected, I think this is Hokkaido.
北海道で、島松旭町3
In Hokkaido, Shimamatsuasahimachi 3.
島松旭町を、探すのじゃ。
Let's search for Shimamatsuasahimachi.
そして、19号通り。
And, 19-go dori.
19号があるらしいのじゃ。一旦進むか。
Apparently, there's Route 19. Let's move forward for now.
ちょっと何というか...
How should I say...
こっちか。こっちの方で、19、島松旭
This way? On this side, 19, Shimamatsu Asahi.
19号...
Route 19...
何かこっちの方な気はしていますのじゃ、島松。
I feel like it's over here, Shimamatsu.
島松旭。てか、旭ってさ、旭ってさ...
Shimamatsu Asahi. Actually, "Asahi"...
この辺に工場なかった？
Wasn't there a factory around here?
この辺に工場があったような気が...島松！
I feel like there was a factory around here... Shimamatsu!
島松あるのじゃ！
There is Shimamatsu!
ふんふんふん。
Hmm hmm hmm.
島松旭町。
Shimamatsuasahicho.
んで、19号...
And, Route 19...
19号って何なんじゃろ？19号...
What is Route 19? Route 19...
19号って何なんじゃ。島松、島松。
What is Route 19? Shimamatsu, Shimamatsu.
道路？
A road?
道路なんじゃろ？
Is it a road?
ちょっと、でも0に寄せるには、もっと情報を得なきゃいけないから、さすがに動くか。
But, to get close to 0, I need more info, so I should move.
動かないものには情報は与えられないのじゃ。どっち行く？
No info is given to things that don't move. Which way should I go?
どっち行くのがいいんじゃろか。
Which way would be best?
川。
A river.
小学校もある。
There's also an elementary school.
柏木川！やった！みんな大好き、島松小！
Kashiwagigawa! Yay! Everyone's favorite, Shimamatsu Elementary!
これ来たんじゃない？川、川、川。
Is this it? River, river, river.
柏木川を、探していきますのじゃ。
Let's search for Kashiwagigawa.
柏木川を探して、いきますのじゃ。柏木川あったのじゃ！
Let's search for Kashiwagigawa. Kashiwagigawa is here!
柏木川、そして島松小。
Kashiwagigawa, and Shimamatsu Elementary.
島松小を探していきますのじゃ。川を、えっと...
Let's search for Shimamatsu Elementary. The river, let's see...
北かな？川の北...川が違うな。
North? North of the river... No, that's the wrong river.
こう流れてるのか。
It's flowing like this.
南北で流れてるのかな？南北で流れていて、
Is it flowing north to south? Flowing north to south,
こっち側に小学校が。島松小、合ってる？
and on this side is the elementary school. Shimamatsu Elementary, is that correct?
島松小がこちらにございますのじゃ。島松小発見。
Shimamatsu Elementary is right here. Shimamatsu Elementary found.
で、今いるのが、ここかな？ここにきていて。
So, where we are now, is it here? We are here.
んで、戻るのじゃ。どっちから来たっけ、わし？
And, let's go back. Which way did I come from?
わし、どっちから来たっけ？よいしょ、よいしょ。
Which way did I come from? Yoisho, yoisho.
あ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
こっちから来てるっぽいのじゃ。
Looks like I came from this way.
うん
Yeah.
リスポーンするのじゃ
I'll respawn.
リスポーンして
Respawn, and...
ここかな？
maybe here?
で、この辺に、多分住宅地が
And around here, there's probably a residential area...
あって、って感じ
...and so on.
な、気がしておりますのじゃ
I have a feeling that's the case.
うん
Yeah.
じゃあ
Then...
いや、こっから寄せるの苦手なのじゃ
No, I'm bad at pinpointing from here!
ええと、左寄り、左よりで
Let's see, a bit to the left... to the left...
左よりで、こっち側で
To the left, on this side...
のじゃ〜
...like this...
こっちかな？こっちとか
Maybe here? Or here?
んで
And...
南に合わせて
...align to the south...
いや、むずいのじゃ！
No, this is hard!
よいしょ！ 2メートルじゃ！
There! 2 meters!
2メートルなのじゃ〜！
It's 2 meters!
近づいてはいるけど、難しいのじゃ
I'm getting closer, but it's hard.
これ完全に寄せきるってめちゃくちゃ難しいのじゃ
Pinpointing this perfectly is insanely hard.
ね。うん、ゼロは運
Right? Yeah, getting 0 meters is just luck.
次行くのじゃ
Going to the next one.
次！
Next!
う〜ん
Hmm...
なんか、高岡市
Looks like Takaoka City.
高岡市多くない？高岡市多いのじゃ。高岡市
Aren't we getting Takaoka City a lot? There's so much of it. Takaoka City...
えーっと、高岡市の中のどこ、という話なのじゃが
Well, the question is where exactly in Takaoka City we are.
どっちに道路あるの？
Which way is the main road?
一旦、南に進んでみるのじゃ
Let's try going south for now.
南に進んでみるのじゃ
Let's go south.
南に進んでみますのじゃ。よいしょ
I'm going south. There we go.
う〜、めっちゃ広い
Whoa, it's so open.
南じゃなかったかの？
Was south the wrong way?
でもここ、川の香りしない？
But wait, doesn't it smell like a river here?
西から川の香りするのじゃ。西から川の香りするから、さすがに
I smell a river from the west. Since it smells like a river to the west, surely...
高岡市のこっち側だと思うのじゃ。これ絶対川だよ
I think it's on this side of Takaoka City. That's definitely a river.
川の香りするのじゃ
It smells like a river.
うん
Yeah.
川の香り...
The smell of a river...
まあ、もうちょい進んでみる。進んでみますのじゃ。よいしょ
Well, let's go a bit further. I'll keep going. Up we go.
建物系がね、あるといいんじゃが
It'd be nice if there were some buildings.
ふんふんふん
Hmm, I see.
よいしょ、よいしょ
There, there...
よいしょ
There...
よいしょ、こっちはもう川じゃからあれかの？
There, is this already the river side, then?
あんまりかの？
Not much here?
うん、やっぱ、ド、ド川。ド川がある
Yeah, as expected, a huge river. There's a massive river.
なるほどね
I see.
なんか、北に進んだほうが、いけるかの？
Maybe it's better to go north?
ちょっと北に戻ってみますのじゃ
Let me try going back north.
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ
There we go, there we go...
黒くなっちゃった
It went black.
土手はあんま情報ないかの？リスポン地点戻って
There isn't much info on the embankment, is there? Back to the spawn point.
こっち進んだから、北に進んでみますのじゃ
I went that way already, so let's try going north.
よいしょ、よいしょ
There we go, there we go.
うん、北に進みましたのじゃ
Okay, I went north.
なんかあるかの？
Is there anything?
もうちょい進むのじゃ。よいしょ
Let's go a bit further. There we go.
よいしょ
There.
どっちから来た？え、どっちから来たかわかんなくなっちゃったのじゃ。もう一回
Which way did I come from? Wait, I lost track of where I came from. Once more...
もう一回チャレンジ
Let's try again.
う〜ん、こっち
Hmm, this way.
こっち
This way.
よいしょ、こっち
There we go, this way.
このまま人間と出会うまで進んで行きますのじゃ
I'll keep going until I find some humans.
ソーラーパネルがめちゃくちゃいっぱいあるのじゃ！
There are so many solar panels!
ソーラーパネルってどこにあるんじゃろう？
I wonder where these solar panels are.
あっ、いたいたいた。あれなんか建物の香り
Ah, there, there, there. That looks like a building.
特にタイトルなし。タイトルなしの建物
No sign on it. It's a building with no sign.
でもなんかスクールバスとか書いてある
But there's something written about a school bus.
え〜、にし、にし...
Let's see, Nishi, Nishi...
の...
...of...
にしひろうえ？にしひろうえを探すのじゃ
Nishihiroue? I'll look for Nishihiroue.
にしひろうえ
Nishihiroue...
でも多分、この、ここの川じゃから。さっき見えた川が
But probably because of this river... the river we saw earlier...
この辺、だと思う。さっき高岡市って書いてあったから多分、
I think it's around here. Since it said Takaoka City earlier, probably...
なんか、あいだのどっかなのかなと予想しておりますのじゃ
I expect it's somewhere in between.
にしひろうえ探したいけど
I want to find Nishihiroue, but...
にしひろうえが、ひろうえから探す？
Should I search for "Hiroue" first?
にしひろうえがわからんのじゃ
I can't find Nishihiroue.
にしひろうえ
Nishihiroue...
にし、ひろ、うえ
Nishi... hiro... ue...
ない
It's not here.
一旦もう一回タイトル見る。あ、にしひろかみって書いてる！
Let me look at the sign one more time. Oh, it says Nishihirokami!
にしひろかみって書いてるのじゃ！で、大門小学校あるよ、大門小学校
It says Nishihirokami! And there's Daimon Elementary School here!
小学校が近くにあるんじゃの？
There's an elementary school nearby, right?
大門小学校が、ある。あり
Daimon Elementary School is... there, got it.
この辺めっちゃ発電所あるから、この、あ、ひろうえある。あ、にしひろうえある！にしひろうえ
There are tons of power plants around here, so... Ah, there's Hirokami. Ah! There's Nishihirokami! Nishihirokami.
ん？にしひろうえあるけど...
Wait, Nishihirokami is there, but...
そもそも川の方角が...
First of all, is the direction of the river...
川が...
Is the river...
こっちじゃから こっちな気がするけど。
over here, so I feel like it's this way.
この川か？ ここの川の可能性もある？
Is it this river? Is there a possibility it's the river here?
んー。
Hmm...
ま、一旦この辺で見ておいて探してみようと思うのじゃ。
Well, I'll search around here for a bit.
んー。
Hmm...
でもやたらとさ、このさ、発電所？変電所？みたいのがあるから、なんかこっちでもおかしくないよね？
But since there are so many of these power stations? Substations? It wouldn't be strange if it were over here, right?
こっちでもおかしくないよね？
It wouldn't be strange if it were here, right?
って思う。思いまつのじゃ。
That's what I think. Yes, I do think so.
んー。
Hmm...
ちょ、一旦ここブックマークしておいて。
Let's bookmark this place for now...
戻るか。
And go back.
ひろかみ？のじゃ？
Hirokami? Is it?
ちょっと一旦リスポーン。
Let's respawn for a second.
リスポーンして、もう一回考え直すのじゃ。
Respawn, and think it over again.
これじゃ嘘、高小西って書いてあるの。
Is this a lie? It says Taka-Konishi...
もっかい北進みますのじゃ、北進むじゃろ。
I'll head north again. Going north...
おいしょ。何、ヒントないかも見つつ、北進むじゃろ。
Oopsy. I'll head north while looking for hints.
田んぼに出るじゃろ。きた、きた。ん？さっきこの道だった？
Going out to the rice fields. Here we go. Wait, was it this road earlier?
さっきと違う道に来ちゃった？ひろかみ... ひろかみでしたのじゃ。失礼いたしましたのじゃ。
Did I end up on a different road? Hirokami... It was Hirokami. My apologies.
え、さっきと違う道に来ちゃった気がするのじゃ。
Wait, I feel like I came to a different road than before.
んー。どこから来たっけ、わし。
Hmm... where did I come from?
橋見つけたい。あ、じゃ、橋を捜しに行くのじゃ。
I want to find a bridge. Ah, then let's go look for a bridge.
多分、西新上大門にいるということは、北に行けば橋があるはずじゃから、一旦北に向かって...
Since I'm probably in Nishi-Shinjo-Daimon, there should be a bridge if I go north, so for now heading north...
てか、土手この辺じゃろ。北に向かって...
Wait, the bank is around here, right? Heading north...
川を、川を北上したくないですか？なんか書いてある。
Don't you want to go up north along the river? Something's written there.
これ読めない？これ読めないのじゃ？ちょっと読ませていただきたいです。おいしょ。
Can't read this? Can't I read this? I'd like to read it, please. Up we go.
うーん、読めないのじゃ。
Hmm, can't read it.
さっき「いすいし」って書いてあったのじゃ。
Earlier it said "Isuishi".
え、わしどこから来たか分かんなくなっちゃった。わしどこから来た、わしどこから来たんじゃろうな。
Wait, I don't know where I came from anymore. Where did I come from? I wonder where I came from.
大門町、大門町来ただ。大門町。大門町捜すのじゃ。この辺大門書いてあるけどね。大門。
Daimon-machi, I came to Daimon-machi. Daimon-machi. Let's look for Daimon-machi. It says Daimon around here. Daimon.
大門町というネーミングにはなっていない感じなのじゃ？もう消えたネーミング？消えたネーミングなのじゃ？
Is it not named Daimon-machi anymore? Is it a name that disappeared? Did it disappear?
合併とかあった？大門町ないけど。
Was there a merger? There's no Daimon-machi, though.
でも大門とは書いてるから、多分名残り、名残りはあるのじゃ。
But it does say Daimon, so there must be some traces of the name left.
大門町？
Daimon-machi?
ふんふんふん。あと何か神社っぽいの。
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm. And something shrine-like.
ふんふんふん。
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
迷子のわしは誰が拾ってくれるんじゃろう。迷子になったらお主らが連れてってくれるの？わしのこと。
Who will pick up this lost me? If I get lost, will you guys take me with you?
え、川がなくなった！
Eh, the river is gone!
え、川、さっきまであった川が... 消えたのじゃ。あ、ある！あるのじゃ！
What? The river... the river that was there just now has disappeared. Oh, there it is! It's there!
西に川がある。え、西に川がある？妙なのじゃ。
There's a river to the west. Wait, a river to the west? That's strange.
妙じゃないのじゃ。え、じゃ、これなのじゃきっと。
No, it's not strange. Oh, then this must be it.
え、これじゃない？わしが見えてたさっきのやつこれじゃない？これ説ない？
Wait, isn't it this? Isn't this the one I was seeing earlier? Is that possible?
八幡社。説ない？そんなことないか。
Hachiman Shrine. Is that possible? No way, right?
あ、これ、こっちの可能性もあるのじゃ。トイレもある。
Ah, there's also a possibility it's this way. There's also a toilet.
ふーん。
Hmm...
川に近づきたいのじゃ。
I want to get closer to the river.
ちょ、川に近づかせていただきますのじゃ。あ、いみずしって書いてあるじゃん。これいみずしなの？
Let me get closer to the river. Oh, it says Imizu City! Is this Imizu City?
川に近づかせていただくのじゃ。おいしょ、おいしょ。これ...
Let's get closer to the river. Oopsy, oopsy. This...
土手に、この北方向の... え、でも北に、北にあるよ。北にあるってことはこっち側な気がするけどな。
By the bank, in this northern direction... Wait, but it is in the north. If it's in the north, I feel like it's on this side.
北にあるってことはこっち側な気がするけど、ダメなのじゃ？
If it's in the north, I feel like it's on this side, but is that no good?
なんかこっちな気がするけど。この辺な気がするけど。さっき見えてたのこれな...
Somehow I feel like it's here. I feel like it's around here. The one I saw earlier...
ここじゃろ絶対、道！こんな角度じゃったよ！絶対この辺じゃろ！
This is definitely the road! It was at this angle! It has to be around here!
って思うんじゃが。絶対ここじゃろ。
I think. It's definitely here.
ちょ、一旦ここだとして。一旦ここだとして。あ、むにゃ...
Wait, assuming it's here for now. Assuming it's here. Ah, munya...
うーん、のじゃ。一旦ここだとして。
Hmm, noja. Assuming it's here for now.
ここだとして、ここだったら...
Assuming it's here, if it was here...
なんか、この辺の市街地のどかなのじゃ。この辺の市街地のどかな気が...
It feels like somewhere in this residential area. Somewhere in this residential area...
さ、3個の道。どこじゃろ。
A thr- three-way junction. Where is it?
なんか、この辺とか。
Like, around here?
この辺な気がするのじゃ。
I feel like it's around here.
進むのじゃ！
Let's go forward!
よいしょ。
Alright.
よい...道ももう一回ちゃんと見とくか。
Let- Let me take another look at the roads.
こうじゃね？
Isn't it like this?
うん、道の角度が一緒なのじゃ。
Yeah, the angles of the roads are the same.
ここなのじゃ？
Is it here?
うん。
Yep.
ここなのじゃーー！
It's here!
え、た、多分。
Uhm, p- probably.
多分ね。
Probably, yeah.
多分ここじゃから、
Since it's probably here...
この辺に置くのじゃ。
...I'll place it around here.
のじゃ！
Go!
ゼロメートルなのじゃーー！
It's zero meters!
ゼロゲス、ゼロゲスなのじゃ。
A zero-meter guess! It's a zero-meter guess!
やったのじゃーー！
I did it!
ふん。
Phew.
難しかったのじゃ。
That was hard.
川に、川に惑わされるのじゃ。
I got confused by the river.
次行くのじゃ！
Next round!
よいしょ。
Let's do this.
うーん。
Hmm.
ふむふむ、ふむふむ。
I see, I see.
なんか情報が多そう。キュッとした家がいっぱいなのじゃ。
Looks like there's a lot of info. Lots of tightly packed houses.
キュッとしてるから、
Since they're packed...
03。
03...
東京か？
Is it Tokyo?
杉並？
Suginami?
ちょっとちゃんと読めないのじゃ。
I can't quite read it properly.
えっと、杉並...
Let's see, Suginami...
宮前5丁目？宮前？
Miyamae 5-chome? Miyamae?
宮前？
Miyamae?
杉並宮前5丁目。
Suginami Miyamae 5-chome.
宮前ってどこなのじゃ？
Where is Miyamae?
ま、一旦...
Well, for now...
一旦、これは宮前5丁目ってのを覚えておいて、
First, let's remember that it's Miyamae 5-chome...
道とかを探した方が早そうなのじゃ、東京じゃし。
...and it might be faster to look at the roads since it's Tokyo.
よいしょ。
There we go.
道に出て行きますのじゃ。
I'll go out to the main road.
南へ。
To the south.
南へ進む。
Going south.
南へ進むと、
If I go south...
のじゃ？
Oh?
のじゃ。
Oh.
あ、くねくねしてる。
Ah, it's winding.
くね、くねくねしてるのじゃ！
It's- It's winding!
くねくねしてるのじゃ！
It's really winding!
川もあるよ。川もあるのじゃ。
There's a river. There's a river!
稲荷、稲荷陸橋？
Inari... Inari Overpass?
川があるから、
Since there's a river,
水探すのじゃ。
I'll search for water.
水...でもこんなに太くないよね？
Water... but it's not this wide, right?
もっと細い川じゃと思うんじゃが。
I think it's a much narrower river...
稲荷陸橋っていうの...杉並広いからなぁ、でも。
"Inari Rikkyo"... Suginami is pretty big, though.
杉並広いのじゃ。杉並から稲荷陸橋を探す。
Suginami is huge. I'll search for Inari Rikkyo from Suginami.
くねくね、稲荷陸橋探さなきゃいけない。
It's winding. I have to find Inari Rikkyo.
川の名前を知りたいのじゃ、橋の名前じゃなくて。
I want to know the name of the river, not the bridge.
橋の名前教えて。
Tell me the name of the bridge.
あ、でもここに住所が書いてある。
Ah, wait, there's an address written here.
ちょっとこれ見るのじゃ。
Let me look at this.
この住所...あ、角度的に見えないのじゃ。
This address... Ah, I can't see it from this angle.
よいしょ。見せて。
Alright... Let me see.
見せて！
Let me see!
飛び出し注意。
"Watch out for children."
飛び出し注意じゃなくて。
Not "Watch out for children."
ちょっと住所見れる場所探すのじゃ。
Let me find a place where I can see an address.
住所見れる場所探して！
Please find somewhere with an address!
よいしょ。
Alright.
なく、なくしたのじゃ。
I- I lost it.
杉並区...あった！
Suginami Ward... Ah, there it is!
久我山3丁目！
Kugayama 3-chome!
久我山をさがすのじゃ。
I'll search for Kugayama.
久我山を探すのじゃ。
Let's look for Kugayama.
フブキ先輩いたのじゃ？
Fubuki-senpai was here?
わしは地図を見てて気づけなかったのじゃ。
I was looking at the map and didn't notice.
配信終わったら見るのじゃ。
I'll watch it after the stream ends.
久我山、ないのじゃ？探すのじゃ。
Kugayama, is it not here? Let's search.
もっと広い道行きたい。
I want to go to a wider road.
え、鉄道？
Wait, a railway?
これ、鉄道なの？
Is this a railway?
本当だーー！
It really is!
鉄道なのじゃ。北に...
It's a railway. To the north...
北に鉄道。
A railway to the north.
北に鉄道...
A railway to the north...
気づかなかったのじゃ。
I didn't notice.
北に鉄道、久我山...
Railway to the north, Kugayama...
情報量が多いのじゃ。
There's so much information.
久我山、久我山...
Kugayama, Kugayama...
探すのじゃ、探すのじゃーー！
I'm searching, I'm searching!
くが、久我山、久我山...
Kuga- Kugayama, Kugayama...
もっと広い道出たい。
I want to get out to a wider road.
広い道に出ます。
Heading to a wider road.
東京は苦手なのじゃ。
I'm not good with Tokyo.
東京のマップは、あまり得意じゃないのじゃ。
I'm not very good with Tokyo maps.
よいしょ。
Alright.
でっかい建造物見つけた...
I found a huge building...
知りたいのじゃ
I want to know.
でっかい建造物
A huge building.
迷子、迷子、迷子
Lost, lost, lost!
こっち進めないっぽい
Looks like I can't go this way.
よいしょ、よいしょ
Alright, alright.
Alright, alright...
ねえ、鉄道ヒントなのじゃ。北に鉄道があったのじゃ。
Hey, there's a railway hint. There was a railway to the north.
あっ、ちょっと安心する。安心するのじゃ、ちょっと。
Ah, that's a relief. Quite a relief, actually.
広めの道にきた
I've come out to a wider road.
久我山稲荷
Kugayama Inari.
久我山らしい、やっぱ
It really seems to be Kugayama, after all.
やっぱ久我山
As expected, Kugayama.
ふむふむ、久我山。駅というのがある
Hmm, Kugayama. There's a station.
駅から探すのがよさそうなのじゃ
It seems best to look starting from the station.
久我山駅というものが
There is a...
ありますのじゃ
...Kugayama Station.
久我山駅探すか
Let's search for Kugayama Station.
じゃ、さっきの、は
Then, the previous one was...
あった久我山駅！めっちゃあるやん！
Ah, there's Kugayama Station! It's right there!
めっちゃありましたのじゃ
It was really right there.
久我山稲荷神社もありましたのじゃ。失礼いたしましたのじゃ。
Kugayama Inari Shrine was also there. Excuse me for that.
そして
And then,
え、じゃ、川とかもさ
Eh, so rivers too, right?
川とかも見つけられそうじゃない？
Don't you think we can find the river too?
なんて川にいたかをもう
Which river we were at...
もう結構忘れちゃったんじゃが
...I've mostly forgotten by now, but...
めっちゃ動いてるのじゃ
It's moving so fast.
あっ、違う。違う、違う、違う
Ah, wait. No, no, no, no.
駐車場にヒントめっちゃ書いてあった気がするのじゃ
I feel like there was a huge hint written in the parking lot.
よいしょ、よいしょ
Alright, alright...
杉並、宮前5丁目
Suginami, Miyamae 5-chome.
ここから
From here...
宮前5丁目を
...I'll search for Miyamae 5-chome...
探す作戦
...that's the plan.
駐車場を探す作戦なのじゃ
The plan is to look for the parking lot.
ここから駐車場を探させていただきますのじゃ
I will now search for the parking lot from here.
探させていただきたいのじゃが
I would like to search for it...
じゃが
...but...
もしくは、この辺の建物の
Or, the name of these buildings...
タイトル、建物のタイトルを知りたいのじゃ
...I want to know the names of the buildings.
え、でも建物のタイトルになり得る建物がない。一軒家ばかり。
But there are no buildings that would have names. Just houses.
タイトルがあるのは、集団住宅じゃから
The ones with names would be apartment complexes...
宮前第3駐車場
Miyamae No. 3 Parking Lot.
タイトルないのじゃ
There are no names here.
うーーん
Hmm...
読み込んでほしいのじゃ
I want it to load.
ふむふむ、宮前5の8
Hmm, Miyamae 5-8.
宮前5の8
Miyamae 5-8.
やっぱ宮前なのじゃ。久我山じゃなくて宮前にいるのじゃ。
It's definitely Miyamae. I'm in Miyamae, not Kugayama.
宮前をさがすのじゃ
I'll search for Miyamae.
さすがにこの辺のどっかに
Surely it's around here somewhere.
ある気がする。そう、ビルとかアパート名、タイトルなのじゃ。
I feel like it is. Yeah, building or apartment names.
宮前、宮前
Miyamae, Miyamae...
ない？
Is it not there?
ないのじゃ？久我山まではいけた。
Not there? I made it to Kugayama.
都会苦手なのじゃ
I'm not good with cities.
情報が多すぎて
There's too much information...
どこを見ればいいか、わかんなくて
...I don't know where to look.
わかんなくて、わかんなくて
I don't know, I just don't know...
宮前、宮前
Miyamae, Miyamae...
西宮
Nishimiya...
西宮？
Nishimiya?
西宮ってことは
Nishimiya means...
もうちょっと東に...宮前！
...a little more to the east... Miyamae!
宮前あったのじゃーー！
Miyamae was there!
たどり着くのがずいぶんと時間を要してしまったようなの
It seems it took quite a bit of time to reach here.
もう一回見るのじゃ
Let me look again.
よいしょ
Alright.
宮前5丁目
Miyamae 5-chome.
5丁目
5-chome...
えっと、1、2
Let's see, 1, 2...
5丁目どこなのじゃ、4
Where is 5-chome? 4...
5丁目ない
There is no 5-chome...
5丁目
5-chome...
駐車場多くない？駐車場めっちゃ多いのじゃ。
Aren't there many parking lots? So many parking lots!
宮前4
Miyamae 4.
宮前4丁目はここなのじゃ
Miyamae 4-chome is here.
駐車場が
The parking lots...
多いですのじゃ
...are numerous.
5丁目今探してます。
I'm looking for 5-chome now.
5丁目あったのじゃ！
5-chome was there!
これが宮前5丁目の予感
I have a feeling this is Miyamae 5-chome.
5丁目の予感
A feeling of 5-chome...
予感なんじゃが
...I have a feeling...
じゃが、ではあって
...but, indeed...
宮前4丁目、5丁目、第5
Miyamae 4-chome, 5-chome... No. 5.
第5じゃって
It says No. 5.
It says No. 5!
いっぱいありすぎてどれが第5かわかんないのじゃ
There are so many that I don't know which one is No. 5.
ちょっとさっき住所見つけたから、もう一回そこ行こう。北に...
I found the address earlier, so let's go there again. To the north...
よいしょ
Alright.
なんか住所書いてあった
Some address was written.
宮前5の8
Miyamae 5-8.
5の8
5-8...
これ
This one.
5の8
5-8.
5の8？
5-8?
5の8
5-8
わからなくなったのじゃ、5の8
I lost track. 5-8.
この辺の駐車場のどっか...
Somewhere in this parking lot around here...
駐車場ってタイトル...あ、「宮前5」って書いてる！
The title of the parking lot... Ah, "Miyamae 5"!
これじゃない？！もしかしてこれ？
Isn't it this?! Could it be this?
違うかな。
Maybe not.
もっかい戻るのじゃ。何度でも。
I'll go back again. As many times as it takes.
宮前五丁目第5。
Miyamae 5-chome, No. 5.
こっから第5じゃろ？でも、地図的におかしくて。
It must be No. 5 from here, right?
But... the map looks weird.
ここにある...
It's here...
イースト...東にあるから。
East... Since it's on the east side.
東にあるから、この辺な気がする。
Since it's on the east side...
I feel like it's around here.
ちょ、道見る。道見るのじゃ。
Wait, let me look at the road.
I'll look at the road.
ん、北...ん、道的に違う。
Mm, north... Mm, the road looks different.
道的に違うのじゃ。
The road is definitely different.
なんか、東にある。
It's like... it's to the east.
三井のリパーク書いてるかな？三井のリパーク。
I wonder if "Mitsui Repark" is written?
Mitsui Repark...
カーシェアだと書いてるのかな？パーキングは多分書いてない感じがするの。
Maybe it's written as "car share"?
It feels like the parking space isn't shown on the map.
信号ね。信号探すのじゃ。
Traffic lights. I'll look for traffic lights.
北に行くと信号があるのかな？
If I go north, is there a traffic light?
5の8。
5-8.
北に行って5の8があるということは...
Going north and having 5-8 means...
北に行って5の8があるということはこの辺？
If going north has 5-8, is it around here?
北に行って5の8。
Going north, 5-8.
ガチむずなのじゃ。
This is seriously hard.
パーキングも大体書いてる。
Usually, parking is written on the map too.
え、じゃあわしが見たパーキング違うのかも。
Eh, then maybe the parking lot
I saw is a different one.
この辺だと思うんじゃが。北進んでみるのじゃ。
I think it's around here.
Let's try going north.
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ！
Yoisho, yoisho, yoisho!
信号...信号あり。
Traffic light... There is a traffic light.
あれ、分からん道来ちゃった。もっかい、もっかい行くのじゃ。よいしょ。
Oh, I came to a road I don't know.
Let me try again, again. Yoisho.
この会計事務所とかで...は、会計事務所ある！え、じゃあ合ってるのじゃ！
With this accounting office...
Oh, there's an accounting office! Eh, then I'm on the right track!
じゃあ合ってたのじゃ！ここなのじゃ！ここでしたのじゃ。よいしょ。
Then I was right! It's here!
It was here. Yoisho.
ということは、ここなのじゃ。
That means... it's here.
ようやく...ようやく...
Finally... Finally...
ここなのじゃ！
It's here!
わあ！東京手強いですのじゃ！
Wah! Tokyo is tough!
手強かったのじゃ。情報量に弱いのじゃ。
It was tough.
I'm weak against too much information.
最後行くのじゃ！
Let's do the last one!
ああ、安心する。開けた道。
Ah, I feel relieved. An open road.
でも、ちょっと...にしてももっと欲しいのじゃ！
But, wait...
still, I want more information!
ちょっと開けすぎている。でも山が...結構山脈。
It's a bit too open.
But the mountains... quite a mountain range.
雪がかかっている山脈があるから...
Since there is a snow-covered mountain range...
結構山で大体の位置が、山さえ分かれば、地方さえ分かれば行けそうな代わりはしていますのじゃ。
If I can identify the mountains, I can guess the general location.
If I can figure out the region, it feels like I can do it.
ので、一旦電柱を探したいのじゃ。
So, first I want to find a utility pole.
よいしょ、よいしょ。
Yoisho, yoisho.
あ、のじゃ...あ、あの...ん？違う、こういう景色なのか。よいしょ、よいしょ。よいしょ、よいしょ、進め進め進め！進め進め！進む進む進む！中山ライオンズクラブ。これなんか、それで特定できる人いそうなのじゃ。
Wait, it's... Ah, uh... Mmh? No, is this just the scenery? Yoisho, yoisho. Yoisho, yoisho, go, go, go! Go, go! Going, going, going! Nakayama Lions Club. This kind of... it feels like someone could locate us using this.
そういうので特定できる人いそうな情報。
Information that feels like someone
could use to locate us.
中山町。
Nakayama Town.
よいしょ。わしはちょっと分からないから進むのじゃ。
Yoisho. I don't really know, so I will move forward.
まだまだ進むのじゃ。
Still going forward.
お、なんか進んでいくと...こっちじゃないような感じ。
Oh, as I go forward...
it feels like it's not this way.
こっちじゃないような感じ。
It feels like it's not this way.
ん、ん。なんか書いてありそう。
Mmh, mmh. There seems to be something written.
よいしょ。見せて。見せて。
Yoisho. Show me. Show me.
山形！
Yamagata!
山形何川...滝川？滝川。お、なんかそういうのあった気がするのじゃ。
Yamagata, which river... Takigawa? Takigawa.
Oh, I feel like there was something like that.
そういう...市があったようななかったような...
There was a city like that, or maybe not...
気がしているのじゃ。
I feel like it.
ま、一旦山形が分かったから、山形で、山が...
Well, since I know it's Yamagata now,
in Yamagata, the mountain...
どこ行っちゃったっけ？ちょっと一旦これチェックポイントにして
Where did I go? Let's make this a checkpoint for now.
山がどっちの方角にあったんだっけ？
Which direction was the mountain in again?
どっちにでかい山が...
Which way is the big mountain...
こっちか。
This way?
えーっと、西。
Let's see, west.
山形のこっち側なのじゃ。
It's on this side of Yamagata.
山形のこっち側。
This side of Yamagata.
中山町発見！
Found Nakayama Town!
これなのじゃ。
This is it.
最上川！
Mogami River!
よいしょ。
There we go.
んで、
And,
さっきはこれは何にしにきたのじゃ？これ土手？
What did we come here for earlier? Is this a bank?
これ何？
What is this?
川管理用通路。何川管理用？
River management path... Which river's management?
す、川... ここの川か？
The... river... Is it this river here?
ここか？ちょっと文字が
Here? The letters are a bit...
文字が潰れて...
The text is blurry...
あ、これで読める。河川。
Ah, I can read it now. River.
別に何か特定の固有名詞ではない。
It's not a specific proper noun.
固有名詞じゃなかったのじゃ。
It wasn't a proper noun.
固有名詞ではなかったけど
It wasn't a proper noun, but...
まあ、山はじゃあ、どっちかの。山じゃない、川。
Well, where is the mountain then? No, not mountain, river.
で、川見つけないとさ...
And if I don't find the river...
でも、川こっちかの？
But is the river this way?
こっからが結構...
From here, it's quite...
こっからが結構長い...
From here, it's a pretty long...
あ、でも、いや、嘘なのじゃ。
Ah, but wait, no, that's not right.
なんか駐車場っぽいのがあるから、なんか施設である可能性があるのじゃ。
There's something like a parking lot, so it might be some kind of facility.
クラブハウス... プレーの、クラブハウス等で、使用権... ご利用される皆様へ
Clubhouse... "For those using the clubhouse etc. and play..."
これがなんかの施設なのじゃ。
So this is some kind of facility.
何の施設かを当てさえすれば
If I can just guess what kind of facility...
いけるかも？
Maybe I can make it?
いけるかもしれないので、施設を当てていくのじゃ。
Maybe I can make it, so let's guess the facility.
え、なんかゴルフみたいなの持ってる。これ何してるのじゃ？
Wait, they're holding something like a golf club. What are they doing?
何持ってるんじゃろ？杖？これはただの杖？
What are they holding? A cane? Is it just a cane?
なんかゴルフな予感がしている。
I have a feeling it's golf.
していて、ゴルフ場とかっこなのかね？
I am, is it like a golf course?
ねえ、なんか...
Look, there's...
そんな感じするけどね。
It definitely feels that way.
ふんふんふん。
I see, I see.
なんか旗とか立ってるし。
There are flags and stuff set up.
北側に、ゴルフ... ゴルフ場。
To the north, a golf... golf course.
こういうね。
Like this, right?
Like this.
こういうね。ひまわりグラウンドゴルフ...
Like this. Himawari Ground Golf...
絶対ここじゃろ！公衆トイレとかあるよ。
It has to be here! Look, there's even a public restroom.
これ、これ、これ、これ、これも、道路もあるよ。
This, this, this, this... there's a road too.
ゲートボール？違うか。じゃ違うか。
Gateball? No? Then maybe not.
でも公衆トイレ2個あるよ。そっちもなかった？
But there are two public restrooms. Wasn't there one over there too?
え、違う可能性があるのじゃ。
Oh, wait, maybe not.
そっちにはなかった気がするのじゃ。
I don't think there was one over there.
のじゃ。
Indeed.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
Heave-ho.
でも、タイトル書いてないね。
But there's no title written there.
タイトル書いてないね。それが気になるのじゃ。
There's no title written. That bothers me.
よいしょ、よいしょ。
Up and up.
ちょっとこっち側にも進んでみて、え、でもトイレ2個あるよ！
Let's move this way a bit. Wait, but there are two restrooms!
え、トイレ2個あるってことは、トイレゲス！
Wait, two restrooms means... restroom guess!
トイレゲスしたら怒る？おぬしら。
Will you guys get mad if I do a restroom guess?
でもなんか...
But it really...
この辺な気がするんじゃが、どうじゃ？
Feels like it's around here. What do you think?
トイレゲスしたら怒る？
Will you be mad if I guess by the restroom?
うん、ちょっと一旦して、
Yeah, let me just place it for now...
え、でもこんな感じな気がするんじゃがのう。
But I really feel like this is the spot.
するんじゃがのう。
Yeah, I really do.
この辺じゃろう。
It must be around here.
ねえ、この道ね。これね。
Look, this road. This one.
これね。
This one, right?
トイレで分かる。
The restroom gave it away.
これ違ったらガチ悔しいのじゃ。いくのじゃ。
I'll be so mad if this is wrong. Let's go.
よいしょ！のじゃーーーー！
Here we go! Oh my gosh!
まさかのトイレゲス。2個。公衆トイレが2個、こんな近いところに。
An unexpected restroom guess. Two. Two public restrooms so close together.
やったのじゃーー！
I did it!
結果を見る。
Let's see the results.
いやー、なかなか時間がかかったの。35分もかかっちゃったのじゃ、全部見つけるのに。
Man, that took a while. It took me 35 minutes to find them all.
何が一番時間かかったの？
Which one took the longest?
4番、4番どれ？
Number 4, which one was number 4?
東京！東京に一番時間かかってるよ！
Tokyo! Tokyo took the longest!
見ておぬしら、この左側でさ、それぞれさ、どれに何分かかったかみたいのがさ、見れるんじゃが、
Look, everyone. On the left, we can see how many minutes each one took.
一番情報量が多いはずの、東京に一番...
Tokyo, which should have the most info, took the longest...
東京に一番時間かかってるのじゃ。
Tokyo took the longest time.
難しいのじゃ。
It's hard.
やっぱね、あのね、東京はね、情報量がね、なかなか多いのじゃ。
You know, Tokyo has so much information.
難しいのじゃ。
It's difficult.
ふん。
Yep.
よいしょ。
There we go.
やったのじゃーー！
I did it!
よいしょ、よいしょ。
All right, all right.
今日は、
Today,
今日のジオゲッサーはこの辺でおしまいにしようかなと思うので、
I think I'll wrap up today's GeoGuessr here,
お部屋、
so my room...
お部屋戻すのじゃ。お部屋...
Let me go back to my room. Room...
戻るのじゃ
Let's go back.
よいしょ
Heave-ho!
のじゃー！
Noja~!
楽しかった。
That was fun.
久しぶりにジオゲッサーやったのじゃ、めちゃ楽しいのじゃ。
It's been a while since I played GeoGuessr, and it was so fun!
ジオゲッサーは楽しいから、いっぱいやりたい。
GeoGuessr is fun, so I want to play it a lot.
いっぱいやりたいですのじゃ。
I really want to play it a lot.
うん。
Yeah.
今日は本当はリズム天国の予定だったんじゃが、
Actually, today I was planning to play Rhythm Heaven, but...
キャプチャーボード、キャプチャーボードがなかなか不調で、
...the capture board, the capture board was acting up...
機材トラブルでできなかったから、
...and due to equipment trouble we couldn't do it,
またいずれ、
so sometime again...
またいずれやらせていただきたいのじゃ。
...sometime again, I'd love to play it.
うん。頑張ったのじゃ。
Yeah. I did my best.
おぬしらジオゲッサーする？普段。
Do you guys play GeoGuessr? Normally?
普段する？一人ではしない？
Do you play normally? Not by yourself?
わし全然一人でもするのじゃ。
I definitely play even by myself.
楽しいのじゃ。
It's fun.
なんか、頭を空っぽにしたい時、
Like, when I want to empty my head...
頭を空っぽにしたい時に、
...when I want to empty my head,
景色を見て、
I look at the scenery...
景色を見てジオゲッサーするのじゃ。
...I look at the scenery and play GeoGuessr.
やんない？
You don't play?
おすすめなのじゃ。
I highly recommend it.
パソコン持ってない？ジオゲッサースマホでもできるよ。
You don't have a PC? You can play GeoGuessr on your smartphone too.
スマホでもね、アプリがあっての、
On smartphones, there is an app, and...
できるのじゃ。
...you can play it.
見るのが好き。世界大会とかそれこそめっちゃ気持ちいいよね。
You like watching? Things like the World Cup are really exciting to watch, right?
できないけどさ、なんかシュパパパパってさ、
I can't do it myself, but they go "shupapapa"...
当てるの、凄くない？
...and guess it right away. Isn't that amazing?
凄いのじゃ。
It's amazing.
今日メラちゃんのグッズ買ってきたのじゃ。あ！グッズ！
"I bought Mela's merch today." Ah! Merch!
今までの配信で何度も何度も宣伝をしようとしてできなかったグッズ。
The merch that I tried to promote over and over in past streams but couldn't.
ゲットしてくれたおぬしら、いるのじゃ？
Are there any of you who got them?
いるのじゃ？
Anyone here?
なんか、なんじゃっけ？
Like, what was it?
公式サイトの方で、
On the official website...
なんか缶バッジとアクスタがもう全部手に入れてくださったみたいな、
...I heard a story that people have already bought up all the can badges and acrylic stands...
話を聞いたのじゃ。聞きましたのじゃ。
...That's what I heard. I did hear that.
光栄ですのじゃ。
I'm honored.
なんか店舗の方でも、店舗の方でもいっぱい手に入れてくださってるとの、噂。
There are also rumors that a lot of people are getting them in physical stores too.
アクスタ、アクスタと缶バッジは、えっと、常設じゃない？あれって。
The acrylic stands and can badges are... aren't they permanent items? Those ones.
レギュラーアウトフィットって多分、
The "Regular Outfit" merch is probably...
なんかまた入荷の可能性あるんじゃない？ちょっとごめん、違ったらごめん。
...likely to be restocked again, right? Ah, sorry, sorry if I'm wrong.
じゃから、嘘と思って聞いてほしいんじゃが、
So, please take it with a grain of salt,
嘘と思って聞いてほしいんじゃが、
please take it with a grain of salt, but...
なんか、あの、今しか買えないのってあれだけ？
...is the only limited-time thing that one?
お祝い周り...お祭り、お祭り周りから出てるやつだけ？
Only the ones from the "Asobimawari" celebration?
ちょっと、ちゃんと把握してないのに喋るの良くないな、こういうの。ちょっと調べよう。
Ah, it's not good to talk about this without fully grasping it. Let me look it up.
調べたいのじゃ。どうやって調べられる？
I want to look it up. How can I look it up?
んーと、
Hmm...
なんか「あそびまわりたい」のXとか見るか。
Maybe I'll look at the "Asobimawari" X account.
Xって言っちゃった。負けた気持ちになる。
I said "X". I feel like I lost.
負けた気持ちになる。負けた気持ちになる。
I feel like I lost. I feel like I lost.
そういうのあるの？うん。
Is there something like that? Yeah.
グッズ情報を探すのじゃ。よいしょ、よいしょ。
Let's look for merch info. Heave-ho, heave-ho.
えーっと、スターティングボイス、
Let's see, the starting voice...
スターティングボイスは、ずっとあるのじゃ。
...the starting voice is permanently available.
スターティングボイスはずっとあるのじゃ。
The starting voice is permanently available.
この先どのタイミングで、
So in the future, at whatever timing,
どのタイミングでわしのこと好きになっても手に入れられるのが、
...at whatever timing you fall in love with me, what you can get is...
スターティングボイス。
...the starting voice.
「本商品は品切れとなった場合、追加販売を行う可能性がございます」あ、じゃあやっぱレギュラーアウトフィット、
"If this product goes out of stock, there is a possibility of additional sales." Ah, so the Regular Outfit merch,
あのアクスタとか缶バッジは、おそらく、おそらく、
...the acrylic stands and can badges, probably, probably,
追加販売があるのではと予想しているのじゃ。断言はしないのじゃ、怖いから。
...I suspect there will be additional sales. I won't say for sure, though, because it's scary.
で、「あそびまわりたい」デビュー記念グッズは、
And the "Asobimawari" debut commemorative merch,
これなんか詳細あったっけ？
...did this have details?
詳細あった？いつまで売ってますみたいな、
Were there details? Like, "available until when"?
あったっけ？
Was there?
なんか、言われていたかの？
Was that mentioned?
なんかね、デビュー記念グッズが5年後も
Well, I don't think debut commemorative merch...
売ってるとは思えないんじゃが、どうじゃ？
...will still be on sale 5 years from now. What do you think?
さすがに5年後にはデビュー記念グッズじゃないグッズじゃろ。
Surely 5 years later, it would be different merch instead of debut commemorative merch.
どうなんだろう。
I wonder how it is.
ちょっと今、公式の情...
Right now, looking at the official info...
方法探してもわかんなかったんじゃ、じゃ。
I couldn't find a way even after looking...
ふむ？
Hmm?
不明なのじゃ。
So it's unknown.
ちょ、不明とさせていただくのじゃ。調べた上で不明とさせていただくのじゃ。
Let's list it as unknown. I searched for it but couldn't find it, so it's unknown.
そういうこともあるのじゃ。うん。
That kind of thing happens too. Yeah.
ので、
So...
気になったお主らは
...if you are interested,
手に入れてくれると嬉しいのじゃ。
I'd be happy if you got one.
そしてあの、グッズゲットしたよ情報も
And I also ego-search to check posts...
エゴサして見てますのじゃ。
...about getting the merch!
ハッシュタグあちちメラで見てますのじゃ。
I check them with the hashtag #achichimela.
なんか、すでに痛バッグとかを
I even saw photos of people who have...
作ったよ、みたいなお写真とかも見て、
...already made things like ita-bags...
ばっかんなのじゃって思ったのじゃ。
...and thought, "Wow, that's amazing!"
すごかったのじゃ。
It was incredible!
アクスタとかもね、こうお出かけに連れてってくれたり、
People also take the acrylic stands with them when going out...
それこそあの、ネポックスのライブで、なんか「メラ、ネポックスだよ」みたいな、
...and at the Nepox concert, some were like, "Look Mela, it's Nepox!"
みたいなのも見たのじゃ。見た。
I saw posts like that too. I did.
なんか色んなところにお出かけ、わしのことを連れてってくださってるのを見ましたのじゃ。
I saw that people are taking me out to various places.
ね、グッズ用のハッシュタグって作った方がいいの？
Say, should I make a hashtag just for merch?
どう思う？あった方がいい？
What do you think? Would it be better to have one?
あった方がいいなら今作る？今作る？
If so, should I make it now? Now?
どうなのじゃ？欲しい？お主ら。
What do you say? Do you want one?
分けた方が分かりやすいかの？
Would it be easier to understand if we separate them?
ネポックスで遊びまわりたいのTシャツ、それはネポックスのTシャツ着てほしいのじゃ。
"The T-shirt for playing around in Nepox" — you should wear a Nepox T-shirt for that!
それはネポックスのなんか着てほしいのじゃ。
You should wear something from Nepox.
作ってほしい？
You want me to make one?
え、どういうタグがいいかの？
What kind of tag would be good?
え、グッズ、グッズとボイスタグ一緒にしてい？
Can I combine the merch and voice tags?
一緒にしてほ、一緒の方が楽じゃの。
Combining them would be easier, wouldn't it?
一緒にしたいのじゃ。
Let's combine them.
何がいいかの？グッズと、
What should we call it? Merch and...
あ、見てみて系、見てみて系、見てみて、
...how about something like "look here"? "Look here..."
みてみてにする？
Shall we go with "look here"?
みて、みてのじゃ、とか。
Maybe "look," "look at this," or something.
みての、どういうのがいいのじゃ？
What kind of tag would be good?
お別れの挨拶決まってるのじゃ。えっとね、初めの挨拶が「のじゃー！」でね、
My farewell greeting is decided! The opening greeting is "Noja!" and...
お別れの挨拶が、えっと、「さらばじゃー！」なのじゃ。
...the farewell greeting is, um, "Saraba ja!" (Farewell!).
別がいい？
Should we have a separate one?
別がいい？もう一緒の方がわしみやすいから一緒でいい？
A separate one? Since it's easier for me to check if they're together, is together okay?
一緒の方がみやすい。
Together is easier to check.
メラちゃんみてみて、メラちゃんみてみて、
"Look Mela-chan," "Look at Mela-chan,"...
あちちみて、あちちみての、
... "Look at Achichi," "Look at Achichi"...
あ、あちちみていいの？あちちみていいじゃん。
Oh, is "look at achichi" good? That sounds great!
うん。
Yes.
えっと、あちちみて。
Okay, "look at achichi" (achichimite).
ひらがなのじゃ。
All in hiragana.
あちちみて。
"achichimite" (あちちみて).
可愛いのじゃ。
That's cute!
It's cute!
あちちみて、で
With "achichimite"...
わしがグッズとかボイスの感想とか
...I want to see your thoughts on the merch and voice packs...
見たいのじゃ。うん。
...and things like that. Yes.
後でTwitterでもこれを報告しようと思うのじゃ。
I'll announce this on Twitter later too.
うん、全部ひらがなが可愛いのじゃ。うん。
Yes, all hiragana is cute. Yep.
ボイスの感想とか、グッズとか、
I want you to post voice pack reviews, merch photos...
こういう風に飾るよ、とかそういうのは
...and how you display them...
あちちみてで投稿してほしいのじゃ。
...with #achichimite!
可愛いのじゃ。
It's cute.
可愛いタグを考えた、
We came up with a cute tag...
わしが考えた、わけじゃないんだけど。
...though I'm not the one who thought of it.
可愛いタグを考えたのじゃ。うん。
But we came up with a cute tag! Yeah.
うん、全部ひらがな。
Yes, all in hiragana.
全部ひらがなであちちみて、なのじゃ。
It's "achichimite" entirely in hiragana.
うん、うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
いい感じなのじゃ。
That sounds perfect.
やったのじゃ。
Yay!
そして、今日伝えきってないことある？
And is there anything else I haven't told you today?
今日伝えきってないこと、あるかな？のじゃ。
Is there anything left to say? Let's see.
えっと、あ、
Well... oh!
明日の枠立てしてないのじゃ。
I haven't set up tomorrow's stream reserve yet!
配信終わったらしよう。
I'll do it after this stream.
配信終わったら、
After the stream...
明日アソビ★まわり隊はじめてのコラボ配信をしようと思うから、
...since we're doing our first Asobi*Mawari-tai collab stream tomorrow...
それの枠を立てるのじゃ。
...I'll set up the stream reserve for it.
ファンアートタグはもうあるのじゃ。メラ画。
The fan art hashtag already exists. It's #melaga.
Twitterのプロフィールに載ってるのじゃ。うん。
It's listed on my Twitter profile. Yes.
ファンアートタグと、あと何じゃ？何があったかの？
The fan art hashtag, and what else? What was there?
ファンアートタグと、
Fan art hashtag, and...
何かもう一個タグあったのじゃ。何だっけ？
...there was one more hashtag. What was it?
配信中タグ！あ、
The stream hashtag! Oh,
メラグミ出動中が配信のやつ。
#melagumishutsudouchu is the one for streams.
キャプチャーは、えっと、明日までに直らなくても、そのSwitchを写す、
Even if the capture card isn't fixed by tomorrow, displaying the Switch...
キャプチャーボードが不調なだけじゃから
My capture card is just acting up,
Switchじゃなくて、
so it's not the Switch...
Switchじゃないゲーム、PCゲームとかは映るのじゃ。
Non-Switch games, like PC games, display just fine.
PCゲームは映りますのじゃ。
PC games will show up.
メンバーシップがいつになるかは分からないのじゃ。
I don't know when membership will be available.
いっぱいの人が見てくださったら
If many people watch my streams,
おそらく、その収益化の条件みたいのが満たせる気がしますのじゃ。
I'll probably meet the monetization requirements.
うん。
Yeah.
明日、月曜日？！
Tomorrow is Monday?!
え！あっというまなのじゃ。
Wait, that was so fast!
あっという間に月曜日になる。ねえ、まだカクカクするのどうすればいいのじゃ、おぬしら？
Monday is here already. What should I do about the stuttering?
直したはずなんじゃが。
I thought I fixed it.
ちょっと、これもいずれ解決した、のじゃあ！
Well, I'll solve this eventually... Nooo!
なんでなのじゃあ！
Why is this happening?!
結構ちゃんとしたパソコン用意したはずなんじゃが。
I'm pretty sure I got a decent PC.
結構ちゃんとしたの、用意したはずなんじゃが。
I'm pretty sure I prepared a really good one,
なぜだか。
but for some reason...
設定もう一回見直そうと思いますのじゃ。
I think I'll look over the settings again.
ちょっとずつ、こういうトラブルが減っていけるように、
So that these kinds of troubles can gradually decrease,
減っていけるようにするのじゃ。
I'll make sure they decrease.
うん。
Yeah.
のじゃ。
Noja.
明日、平日なのじゃ。
Tomorrow is a weekday.
おぬしら、平日嫌？
Do you guys hate weekdays?
GPUでエンコードする設定に今日変えたはずなんじゃが。
I'm pretty sure I changed the encoding setting to GPU today.
なぜこんなことに。
Why is this happening?
「明日は月曜日なのじゃ」と言ってくださいなのじゃ？
You want me to say "Tomorrow is Monday, noja"?
明日は月曜日なのじゃあ！
Tomorrow is Monday, nojaaa!
月曜日
Monday...
なのじゃ。
noja.
平日は、
On weekdays,
おぬしら、お仕事とか、学校とかあるから、
you guys have work or school,
あれかのう？やっぱり、配信見るの難しい？
so is it hard for you to watch streams?
リアルタイムとかだと、やっぱり、お仕事中だったり、するかのう？
If it's live, are you usually at work?
今もお仕事中で、今、今のこのわしの発言をアーカイブで聞いてる人もいるかもしれないのじゃ。
Maybe there are some who are at work right now, listening to this on archive.
ありがとうなのじゃ。
Thank you, noja.
夜なら大丈夫？
Is night time okay?
なんでそんなこと言うのって、言えって言われましたのじゃ！
"Why do you say that?" I was told to say it!
誘導なのじゃ、誘導されたのじゃ！
It was a setup, I was set up!
今、今、わし、わしは今、
Right now, I...
あ、でも、誘導されたと他責するのは、配信者としては、あれかのう？
Ah, but is it bad for a streamer to shift the blame to being set up?
やはり、すべての発言に責任を持つべきじゃから、
After all, I should take responsibility for all my remarks,
やはり、事実陳列罪というものがあって、気をつけるのじゃ。
since there is such a thing as "displaying the truth," I have to be careful.
気をつけますのじゃ。
I will be careful.
うん、気をつけようと思いますのじゃ。
Yes, I will try to be careful.
火の用心じゃ。
Beware of fire.
怖いのじゃ。
It's scary.
誘導されても、誘導されたら何言ってもいいわけじゃないのじゃ。
Even if I was set up, it doesn't mean I can say anything.
ちゃんと自分で思考して、
I must think for myself,
ちゃんと自分で選択して、
make my own choices,
した上で、発言しますのじゃ！
and then speak!
うん、気をつけるのじゃ。
Yes, I must be careful.
気をつけますのじゃ。
I will be careful.
知ってますのじゃ。
I know.
うん。
Yeah.
じゃから、明日からは、
So, from tomorrow onwards,
19時、19時に配信がだいたいあって、
the stream will usually be at 7 PM,
水曜日は、朝の7時、朝の7時に配信がありますので、
and on Wednesday, we have a stream at 7 AM,
通学中とか、通勤中とか、準備中とかに見てほしいのじゃ。
so I'd love for you to watch while commuting or getting ready.
応援してほしい？がんばれ、おぬしら！
Do you want me to cheer you on? Do your best, guys!
生活、人間としての、社会に適合するための生活、応援してるのじゃ！
I'm cheering on your life as a human adapting to society!
がんばれなのじゃ。
Do your best!
わしは、パソコンがんばって直すのじゃ。
I will do my best to fix my PC.
わしはがんばってパソコン直すのじゃ。
I will try my best to fix my PC.
応援してますのじゃ。
I'm rooting for you.
うん。
Yeah.
アーカイブでも見る？
You'll watch the archives too?
うれしいのじゃ。アーカイブでまで見てくれるのうれしいのじゃ。
I'm happy you'll even watch the archives.
コメントとかもね、アーカイブ勢の人とかもね、してくれてるの見てるんじゃ。
I see comments from the archive viewers too.
すごい嬉しい、嬉しいのじゃ。
I'm really, really happy.
うん。
Yeah.
なんか、元気だしたくなったら、歌ってみた動画とか聞くと、元気でるかもしれないのじゃ。
If you want to cheer up, listening to my song covers might help.
ん
Mhm.
よし 話したいこと話せた気がするのじゃ
Alright, I feel like I've talked about everything I wanted to.
話せたのじゃ
Yes, I did.
だから 今日はおしまい！
So, that's it for today!
今日の配信はおしまいなのじゃ
Today's stream is over.
もっかい最後のご挨拶教える
Let me teach you the final greeting again.
お面外してほしい？
Do you want me to take off my mask?
えっと
Let me see...
すぐ外す すぐ外すのじゃ
Take it off right away... I'll take it off right away!
最後の挨拶するのじゃ！
Let's do the final greeting!
最後の挨拶は
The final greeting is...
さらばじゃーで
...\"Saraba-ja!\"...
おねがいしますのじゃ
...so please say that with me.
おぬしら準備はいい？
Are you guys ready?
いくのじゃ！
Here we go!
それじゃ また明日の配信で会うのじゃ
Well then, let's meet again in tomorrow's stream.
さらばじゃー！
Saraba-ja!
ご視聴感謝なのじゃ！
[Thank you for watching!]